<?xml version='1.0' encoding='windows-1251'?>
<string_table>

	<string id="st_af_itcher_name">
		<text>Itcher</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_itcher_descr">
		<text>Formed under high temperatures, the Itcher artifact consists of two distinct layers. Its surface is a solid, dense metamorphic rock, deeply scarred across its entire body. On the inside, a soft, yellowish glowing core of unknown organic origin resides. A thermal artifact capable of shielding its bearer from moderately high temperatures, it transfers part of the absorbed heat to the owner, providing warmth. In return, it drains a small amount of the user’s life force to sustain itself and weakly attracts electricity. Extremely popular among beginners. Causes persistent skin itching—excessive scratching may lead to minor bleeding. Generates a weak gravitic field, reducing backpack weight and offering slight protection against tearing forces. Exhibits moderate radioactivity and is moderately priced.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string> 

	<string id="st_af_pin_name">
		<text>Pin</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_pin_descr">
		<text>A small artifact formed by thermal anomalies in the Zone under extreme temperatures. This artifact appears to have once been an organ of a vascular plant. Further studies have shown that other organic tissues are tightly bound deep within it. Unfortunately, the only way to utilize this artifact is to embed it into one's own body—an act that, aside from being traumatic, causes minor yet persistent bleeding, as the artifact actively inhibits blood coagulation. Despite the discomfort, this process produces a mild sobering effect. It offers decent protection against high temperatures, provides warmth, slightly energizes the body, and increases tissue resistance to tearing. However, it simultaneously feeds on the owner's life force. Some stalkers claimed it could grow deeper into the body and eventually take control over it. Yet this is most likely due to the artifact slightly reducing psi-protection and inducing feelings of anxiety—making such tales just another piece of stalker folklore. Fair price, low radioactivity.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string> 

	<string id="st_af_fireball_name">
		<text>Fireball</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fireball_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed within thermal anomalies from reddish crystals. A spherical formation resembling solidified lava, emitting a faint reddish glow. Its surface is uneven, marked by characteristic luminous fissures, with color ranging from deep red to near black. The artifact maintains a constant temperature of approximately 24&#8239;°C (75&#8239;°F), regardless of the surrounding environment. Because of this, it absorbs heat from its immediate vicinity, creating a thermal barrier around its bearer that effectively protects against direct contact with fire and extreme heat. Appears to feed on radiation, as it absorbs it quite efficiently. For these benefits, it extracts a price in the form of the owner’s life force and energy, while also increases thirst and slightly reducing psi-protection. Additionally, it makes bodily tissues marginally more susceptible to mechanical damage and tearing. May induce hallucinations, thermophobia, and panic attacks. Moreover, despite offering protection from heat, it weakens the body’s resistance to chemical burns—likely due to alterations in skin structure and suppressed cellular regeneration. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gelion_name">
		<text>Helion</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gelion_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of a double sphere: one outer lattice-like shell of molten magma color, and an inner core of incandescent yellow. Its unique feature is the presence of a significant amount of helium—a rare element on Earth, typically found in areas of volcanic activity or thermal anomalies. It is believed that helium acts here as an energy catalyst, stabilizing the artifact’s internal processes and enabling efficient interaction with thermal energy. The outer sphere absorbs excess heat from the surrounding air and channels it inward, maintaining a stable thermal equilibrium. The inner sphere generates a protective field capable of melting fast-moving objects—such as bullets or shrapnel—at close range, while also repelling mutants through high-frequency thermal emissions. However, the artifact’s operation requires constant energy supply. It actively consumes the bearer’s biological energy, using blood as both conductor and medium to sustain its internal functions. The helium-rich structure appears to disrupt normal blood coagulation and tissue regeneration, causing even minor injuries to remain open and heal extremely slowly. Highly radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_plasma_name">
		<text>Plasma</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_plasma_descr">
		<text>A sphere composed entirely of stable, incandescent plasma that does not dissipate in the air. Scans have revealed traces of ash within its structure—remnants of beings consumed in fire anomalies such as the "Hot Spot." Rumors persist that some stalkers have spontaneously combusted, leaving behind only this artifact. There is no confirmed evidence, but frequent discoveries of Plasma near burn zones are hard to ignore. It efficiently absorbs excess heat and psi-waves, converting them into light and toxic particles while warming the bearer. However, interaction with chemical substances—such as acid vapors or aggressive gases—may trigger a sudden release of accumulated toxins. This results in a temporary drop in chemical resistance and increases the risk of poisoning. To maintain stability, Plasma actively drains the owner’s life force, manifesting as rapidly declining stamina—any physical effort, even minor, becomes significantly harder. Additionally, the artifact induces intense thirst and slightly increases hunger, likely due to accelerated metabolism and cellular dehydration. Physically dense and heavy, despite its plasma composition. Extremely radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_part_monolit_name">
		<text>Monolith Star</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_part_monolit_descr">
		<text>A mysterious artifact. There is a legend about its origin: when the Monolith followers first entered Pripyat, they built an altar and prayed to the "Monolith," begging for a sign that it still existed and had not abandoned them. And when their prayer ended, the artifact fell from the sky, landing directly atop the altar. The awestruck fanatics believed this was a direct sign from the "Monolith" itself. Whether true or not, scientists suggest it may form from the merging of certain atmospheric anomalies. Researchers lean toward the theory that the artifact arises from the fusion of air and thermal anomalies, most commonly in areas of intense heat exposure. It possesses a pronounced protective effect, significantly increasing the skin’s resistance to thermal and chemical burns. When exposed to heat, it triggers a process of local stabilization of cellular structures, preventing tissue overheating. However, this protection demands energetic compensation. The artifact actively consumes the bearer’s life force, leading to chronic exhaustion with prolonged use. Its effect on the body’s water balance is particularly strong—intense thirst emerges even in cool environments. Extremely radioactive. Very rare. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_hell_generator_name">
		<text>Hellfire Generator</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_hell_generator_descr">
		<text>A new artifact that has only recently appeared in the Zone. Presumably, a mutated version of the old "Generator" that was exposed to a powerful thermal anomaly. It has lost its original properties, but gained new ones: it offers exceptional protection against thermal effects, reducing them to almost zero. There were even attempts to use it to extinguish fires—with considerable success. It also provides solid resistance to electric current: absorbing most of the charge and neutralizing discharges, while redirecting a small portion to the bearer, replenishing their energy. This effect is felt as a faint tingling and a brief surge of strength. However, the artifact has a serious side effect—it drastically increases thirst. This is linked to the intense cellular-level moisture consumption caused by the artifact’s internal thermoregulatory mechanism. There have been unconfirmed reports suggesting the artifact can become unstable and transform into a "burner" If true, then at least no one has lived to tell the tale. Extremely radioactive. Rare. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,160,0]Thermal Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	

	<string id="st_af_soul_name">
		<text>Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_soul_descr">
		<text>A semi-transparent spherical formation composed of a green-hued core surrounded by a dark-blue substance and encased in a glass-like shell. Emits a bluish-green glow. A unique organic artifact known for its unusual ability to secrete a slime that, through means still unknown to science, slightly increases the body’s overall regeneration rate after injuries of any kind, while simultaneously reducing pain. Additionally, the artifact slightly dampens the effects of psi-waves on the bearer.
Negatively affects stamina, draining a small portion to fuel the body’s healing. At the same time, its slime slightly softens bodily tissues, making them more vulnerable to tearing.
A lightweight, fragile healing artifact. Priced above average due to its practicality and collector’s demand—many believe it resembles a soul trapped within a glass sphere.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_cristall_name">
		<text>Crystal</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed in anomalous zones under high temperatures and in the presence of heavy metals. A cluster of crystals of unknown origin, displaying uneven coloring—from raspberry at the base to bluish-white at the tip. Aside from its striking appearance, it boasts remarkable advantages for a mid-tier artifact: it is non-radioactive and even slightly reduces radiation in the body by absorbing it (does it feed on it?). It mildly accelerates natural tissue regeneration and slightly increases heat resistance. However, since it only speeds up the body’s innate healing processes, the organism expends more of its own resources, leading to faster physical and mental fatigue. Can be sold for a decent sum.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_name">
		<text>Seed of the Oasis</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_oasis_heart_descr">
		<text>A replica of the legendary artifact discovered by Major Degtyarev at the heart of the "Oasis" anomaly. It appears as a crystallized emerald plant, suspended and rotating within a pulsating, transparent, gel-like sphere emitting a faint bluish glow. Its properties only partially mirror those of the original, yet possess unique characteristics of their own. The artifact actively restores health, accelerating wound healing and tissue regeneration even after severe injuries. Simultaneously, it improves psychological well-being. Preliminary data suggests this is due to the artifact synthesizing biologically active substances similar to carbohydrates, proteins, and fats, partially offsetting the body’s energy expenditure. However, the process remains incompletely understood—scientists believe the "Seed" modifies metabolism, converting anomalous energy into beneficial compounds. But this benefit comes at a price. The artifact causes pronounced fatigue: the bearer feels increasingly drowsy, especially after physical exertion. Reactions become sluggish, and dizziness becomes a constant companion. Additionally, it reduces resistance to heat, electricity, and mechanical damage, while amplifying the effects of toxic chemical exposure. Non-radioactive and weakly eliminates accumulated radionuclides. Highly valued in scientific circles, but rarely used by stalkers due to its dangerous side effects.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>

	
	<string id="st_af_pero_fenixa_name">
		<text>Phoenix Feather</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_pero_fenixa_descr">
		<text>A thin, golden-red structure resembling a feather or a bundle of blood vessels. Lightweight and easy to carry. Highly radioactive—requires protection against ionizing radiation. Increases vulnerability to fire and electric effects: prolonged exposure without protection may result in third- to fourth-degree burns, especially on areas with thin skin. Possesses a pronounced regenerative effect, accelerating the recovery of vital functions and promoting tissue healing. Also noted to slightly increase carrying capacity and improve thermoregulation—the artifact emits mild heat, beneficial in cold zones. Through an unknown mechanism, it enhances concentration and reduces fatigue, likely due to influence on the central nervous system. Within its area of effect, free liquid undergoes localized evaporation—condensation, sweat, and moisture in tissues gradually dry out. In rare cases, unprotected individuals nearby have experienced spontaneous micro-bleeding in soft tissues. Scientists hypothesize that the artifact affects capillary permeability or induces local fluctuations in vascular pressure. Rumored to even cure certain fatal illnesses. There’s a belief that finding this artifact brings either immense luck or severe hardship—situations in which the artifact itself becomes essential. Because of this, attitudes toward it remain deeply divided.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_rainbow_pipe_name">
		<text>Rainbow Reed</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_rainbow_pipe_descr">
		<text>An artifact consisting of a rigid central stem with ten curved appendages attached—two yellow, four red, and four green. Possesses an extremely potent vital effect. A strong and consistent sobering effect is observed—eliminates dizziness, restores coordination, and counteracts the aftereffects of toxic exposure. The exact mechanism remains unclear, but researchers suspect influence over the vestibular system and neurotransmitter metabolism. Emits slight heat, providing minimal warmth in cold zones. Increases tissue resistance to thermal and chemical damage. However, it triggers severe bleeding even from previously healed wounds, feeding the artifact’s regenerative and protective capabilities with the bearer’s own blood. For this reason, it's advisable to find a safe, quiet place to regenerate. Extremely radioactive and expensive, prized both for its powerful properties and striking appearance. Collectors and scientists alike are eager to obtain it. Highly radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_joker_name">
		<text>Joker</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_joker_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of two fan-like structures joined perpendicularly. Presumably formed through the simultaneous interaction of three different anomalous fields. Extremely effective at restoring life force—makes medkits practically obsolete. Rumored to even heal tumors. Also increases tissue resistance to thermal and chemical burns, and provides pleasant, consistent warmth. However, it severely thins the blood, making even the slightest bleeding potentially fatal. Named after the nickname of the first stalker who discovered it—Vovan Joker. Unconfirmed reports suggest the artifact may influence the human genotype. Extremely radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_dark_soul_name">
		<text>Dark Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_dark_soul_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of a central sphere, surrounded by two layers of floating fragments of orange and green matter. The red and green material provides excellent protection against chemical and thermal burns, while also emitting steady warmth. Possesses a powerful vital effect—greatly accelerating health recovery, even from critical injuries. Under conditions of stable nutrition and hydration, the regeneration process approaches the very limits of human biological potential. However, this effect comes at a steep cost: the body’s resources are consumed at an accelerated rate. Hunger and thirst set in two to three times faster than under normal conditions, requiring constant replenishment of food and water supplies. Without this, the regenerative effect diminishes sharply, potentially leading to weakness, dehydration, and nervous system breakdowns. It earned its name from a stalker legend claiming the artifact contains the soul of a deceased member of C-Consciousness. Allegedly, even in death, the Zone refused to release spirit, instead manifesting it as this powerful object. Unconfirmed rumors circulate about the artifact’s potential influence on human genotype, though these are likely mere speculation. It’s said that outrageously wealthy individuals, major private military companies, and even certain governments have launched large-scale expeditions into the Zone—solely in search of this artifact. Extremely radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,213,70,125]Vital
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>

	
	<string id="st_af_bracelet_name">
		<text>Bracelet</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_bracelet_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed from common bryophyte plant species under intense exposure to radiation and chemical anomalies. An organic formation shaped like a bracelet, offering weak protection against chemical particles and aiding the owner’s metabolism, slightly enhancing regeneration and wound healing. To fuel this effect, it draws on the bearer’s own energy, resulting in reduced stamina and slightly decreased resistance to all forms of physical impact. Due to its complex structure, some scientists believe the artifact has artificial origins. One theory suggests it was originally an ordinary bracelet that fused with plant matter inside an anomaly. Reasonably priced.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string>  
	
	<string id="st_af_blood_name">
		<text>Stone Blood</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_blood_descr">
		<text>A yellowish-red formation composed of compressed and fossilized remains of plants, soil, and animal debris. A very common artifact. It filters out a certain amount of toxic particles, possesses weak healing properties, and generates a slight anti-gravitational field. During use, it slightly softens bodily tissues, reducing resistance to all forms of physical impact. Some stalkers refuse to use it, disgusted by the fact that human remains are often found within its composition. Moderate price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_name">
		<text>Meat Chunk</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_mincer_meat_descr">
		<text>This artifact has a soft, porous texture resembling skin and is capable of compression. Some stalkers believe it is literally a chunk of skin torn from some unfortunate soul caught in an anomaly and transformed beyond recognition. It filters a significant amount of toxic particles, absorbing them like a sponge, while simultaneously charging the body and increasing stamina. Like Stone Blood, it restores life force when pressed against the skin—but does so more effectively. However, it also softens tissues even more drastically, reducing resistance to physical damage. Superstitions surrounding it are much the same as those tied to Stone Blood. There are also rumors—unconfirmed—that carrying it may increase the risk of ending up in a meat grinder. Decent price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_emerald_name">
		<text>Emerald</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_emerald_descr">
		<text>An anomalous crystal of intense emerald green, distinguished by exceptional optical and structural clarity. It filters out a significant portion of toxins, effectively removes radiation, and stabilizes the owner’s blood pH, resulting in more controlled breathing and increased endurance. However, the artifact possesses pronounced corrosive properties: upon contact with metal, skin, or fabric, it gradually breaks them down at the molecular level. Stalkers who carry it without proper insulation often suffer burns, and report deterioration of buckles, fasteners, and armor components. It is strongly advised to store and wear the crystal only in a sealed, inert container. The crystal is extremely fragile. If physically damaged, it instantly discharges its accumulated anomalous energy—resulting in an explosion. In most cases, not even ash remains to bury. Collectors outside the Zone are highly eager to acquire one for their private collections. Combined with its powerful beneficial effects and relatively straightforward drawbacks, this makes its price one of the highest among all known artifacts. It is said that if you look through its facets at just the right angle, you can glimpse the anomalous flows of the Zone—and sometimes, even the past or the future.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_studen_name">
		<text>Jelly</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_studen_descr">
		<text>An anomalous spherical formation composed of a slimy, fleshy outer layer and a gelatinous core. Scanning results indicate it consists of everything that was caught in the "Kisiel" anomaly, primarily organic matter. The gelatinous core itself is made of an unknown substance—simultaneously metallic and biologically alive. The fleshy shell secretes a slime that provides excellent protection against chemical agents and psi-waves, while also significantly boosting the owner’s regeneration. The artifact is extremely radioactive and acts as a strong conductor of electricity due to the unique structure of its core, drastically reducing electrical resistance. It also generates its own internal gravitational field to maintain structural integrity, substantially increasing backpack weight and reducing maneuverability. Relatively expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>
		
	<string id="st_af_virus_name">
		<text>Virus</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_virus_descr">
		<text>The artifact resembles a schematic model of a virus. One of the most powerful artifacts known, it provides exceptional protection against chemical burns—enough to allow its bearer to move through areas where even a scientific-grade hazmat suit would long ago have melted. It also offers solid defense against psi-effects by resonating with and neutralizing aggressive psi-waves, while maintaining a constant body temperature of 37.2 degrees Celsius around the owner. However, it is a parasitic artifact: it continuously drains the bearer’s life force and energy. Some scientists believe it may actually be a living organism.   Not particularly popular among stalkers, but traders and researchers will practically tear it from your hands—on the Outside, a cure for a particularly dangerous virus has been developed using its properties. As a result, its price is extremely high. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_caterpillar_name">
		<text>Plasma Caterpillar</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_caterpillar_descr">
		<text>An artifact that closely resembles an actual caterpillar. First discovered in Limansk, far from any known anomalies, it was initially mistaken for a new creature within the Zone. Some believe it forms when multiple artifacts are caught in the "Fruit Punch" anomaly, or during the merging of the "Vortex," "Springboard," and "Gas" anomalies. Preliminary data suggests it has no negative properties. The artifact exhibits no obvious harmful effects, but requires careful handling. It provides high resistance to chemical burns, creating a stable protective barrier on the skin and clothing. It secretes a thin layer of transparent slime that instantly absorbs any liquid on contact. This includes minor wounds—when the slime touches them, they close within seconds. This same slime is highly viscous and forms an additional protective coating: it partially disperses bullet impacts, reduces damage from mutant bites and claws, and slows down fast-moving projectiles. The slime itself is nearly weightless, but its viscosity creates slight resistance to movement—particularly noticeable during running or sharp turns. The effect is not critical, but becomes apparent over prolonged use. There’s a curious old stalker tale claiming you can swim through "Fruit Punch" with this artifact. Rumors also persist that when a stalker sleeps, and if the container isn’t tightly sealed, the artifact may crawl in through the mouth and attach itself to an internal organ—or even begin to control the host. There is no credible evidence to support this chilling story… Extremely radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,200,255,0]Acid Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>

	
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_name">
		<text>Sparkler</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_sparkler_descr">
		<text>An artifact appearing as an amorphous, very lightweight spherical formation that periodically emits sparks. Slightly increases the owner’s stamina, allowing for a bit more running, and provides minimal protection against physical impacts. Weakly stabilizes fluctuations in electrical field voltage. Slightly reduces psi-protection and may induce feelings of anxiety. Causes numbness when in contact with bare skin. Radioactive and inexpensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_name">
		<text>Flash</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_flash_descr">
		<text>A semi-transparent spherical formation with a bluish glow, emitting short bursts of bright light and tiny electrical discharges. Serves as an effective energy source—a quality both scientists and stalkers have already learned to exploit. Increases the owner’s speed and reflexes, allowing them to dodge a limited number of bullets, and heals minor wounds. However, it slightly reduces resistance to electricity and toxic particles. The artifact draws heat from the body, causing a sensation of cold even in warm environments. Additionally, it increases the body’s energy expenditure: more calories are required to maintain core temperature. This effect is likely due to an elevated metabolism stimulated by the artifact. Radioactive. Fairly expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_name">
		<text>Moonlight</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_electra_moonlight_descr">
		<text>A legendary spherical artifact, semi-transparent and azure in hue, with white streaks resembling frozen electrical discharges. Emits a soft bluish glow, giving it a calm, almost lunar appearance. Significantly boosts the owner’s energy and strength, infusing the body with power, enabling faster and longer running, and slightly increasing carrying capacity. The artifact resonates with psi-waves, partially neutralizing their effects. At the same time, it exerts a calming influence on the mind, making it especially valuable for stalkers spending prolonged periods in psi-active zones. To sustain its activity, the artifact cools the owner’s tissues and consumes their life force. Extended use may lead to exhaustion, lowered body temperature, and slowed regeneration. Additionally, Moonlight attracts electrical discharges, making it dangerous in areas with high electromagnetic activity. Due to its rarity, striking beauty, and beneficial properties, the artifact is highly prized by both collectors and stalkers. Rumors suggest deeper studies of Moonlight outside the Zone have drawn interest from military sectors, exploring the potential weaponization of its energy. Expensive and moderately radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_electronova_name">
		<text>Elektronova</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_electronova_descr">
		<text>A member of the electrostatic artifact family, named for its striking luminosity. A rare artifact found only in areas of high energy activity. Significantly increases stamina, reflexes, and agility, and generates a weak protective dome that deflects fast-moving objects—likely due to an electromagnetic field surrounding the body. Sensitive to high temperatures—when overheated, it may explode, causing third-degree burns. To prevent this, the artifact actively cools itself and its bearer, producing a sensation of cold even in warm environments. This cooling process demands energy, raising the body’s metabolic costs. As a result, the owner requires 2–5 additional hours of sleep for full recovery. Extremely radioactive. Equally expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_luminewheel_name">
		<text>Shining Wheel</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_luminewheel_descr">
		<text>Originally discovered by a lucky stalker at the Zemsnaryad Station in the Flooded Zone, the artifact was first known as the "Altered Wheel"—and back then, it did little more than emit strong radiation. Since then, smaller copies with new properties have begun appearing across the northern parts of the Zone.   A highly potent energy artifact, it dramatically increases the owner’s stamina. Stalkers claim that with it, one could cross the entire Zone without growing even slightly tired—though no one has yet dared to test this claim. It also provides solid protection against psi-waves. Crafted from an unknown living metal, it is extremely vulnerable to corrosion and electricity, greatly reducing resistance to toxins and acting as an excellent conductor. The metal also siphons heat from the body upon even the slightest contact with skin. Additionally, it is quite heavy. Due to its extremely high radioactivity, the artifact glows intensely. You, too, will light up the surroundings like a beacon—if you neglect proper radiation shielding. Very expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_precious_battery_name">
		<text>Precious Battery</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_precious_battery_descr">
		<text>A mutated version of the "Battery" artifact, now containing inclusions of precious metals and tiny crystals of unknown origin. Very rarely found within the "Electra" anomaly. The artifact greatly enhances physical capabilities: it stimulates energy production in muscles, blocks pain receptors, and alters pyruvic acid metabolism, allowing the bearer to run and move at high intensity for extended periods without fatigue. Presumably powered by electricity, it will inevitably attempt to recharge from the nearest electrical source—including the "Electra" anomaly itself. However, the artifact emits weak infrasonic waves, barely audible but creating constant pressure on the vestibular system and nervous system. Additionally, its internal structure has an unstable resonant frequency. In rare cases—especially when exposed to strong electromagnetic fields—it begins to resonate, emitting faint but unpleasant squeaking sounds reminiscent of metal scraping. This is caused by vibrations in the crystal lattice under the influence of internal energy flow. Extremely radioactive. Its price is significantly higher than other artifacts of similar tier, due to its unique structure—any trader would be glad to acquire such a striking and valuable specimen.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_oblivion_lost_name">
		<text>Oblivion Lost</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_oblivion_lost_descr">
		<text>A bluish-white sphere with internal electrical discharges, resembling the "Moonlight" artifact. Preliminary data suggests it has no negative properties. The artifact effectively resets key metabolic and neuroregulatory processes: it modulates brain signals, increases sweating, stabilizes hormone and amino acid production. This results in a constant sensation of energy saturation—fatigue barely sets in, and high physical activity can be sustained for hours. One of its side effects is near-total suppression of hunger: the body stops demanding food, likely due to the artifact’s internal energy field partially compensating for caloric expenditure. However, this does not mean the body no longer needs recovery. Despite the lack of appetite, the need for water and sleep increases dramatically. Dehydration occurs faster due to heightened perspiration and a hidden cellular-level water imbalance. Additionally, the bearer may require up to 8 extra hours of sleep for full central nervous system recovery. A weak protective field forms around the head, reflecting psi-emissions and reducing anxiety. Still, there are unconfirmed reports of long-term negative effects on the central nervous system and gastrointestinal tract—particularly stomach and intestinal atrophy in prolonged users. However, the data is too scattered to be taken seriously at this stage. Extremely radioactive. Equally expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,0,200,255]Energy
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>

	
	<string id="st_af_sponge_name">
		<text>Sponge</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_sponge_descr">
		<text>A purple, soft artifact resembling a sea sponge. Springs back to its original shape after being touched or squeezed, just like a sponge. Instead of water, it absorbs a small amount of psi-waves, calming the bearer. Slightly accelerates wound healing and provides weak protection against physical damage. Accumulates a portion of toxic particles within itself, which may negatively affect the owner in chemically hazardous areas. Some scientists claim it is a living organism. Moderate price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string> 
	
	<string id="st_af_lobster_eyes_name">
		<text>Lobster Eyes</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_lobster_eyes_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like two fused eggs. Its outer surface is exceptionally thick, and scientists believe the high density of the formation may be the primary reason for its deep, dark hue. The most unequivocal benefit of “Lobster Eyes” is its ability to enhance resistance to psi-impact: it resonates in response to psi-waves, absorbing their dangerous effects to a significant degree. A mild calming effect is also observed—reduced heart rate and diminished feelings of anxiety. In high-temperature zones, it can overheat severely, causing second- to third-degree burns. Radioactive and valuable.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_black_spray_name">
		<text>Black Spray</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_black_spray_descr">
		<text>Formed from vascular plants exposed to anomalous fields, this artifact exhibits a remarkable ability to resonate under psi-wave influence. Over the years, stalkers have learned to tune Black Spray so that it resonates in phase with the primary radiation source, effectively neutralizing or significantly reducing psi-effects. It generates a black liquid that is moderately toxic, lowering the bearer’s chemical resistance. However, it possesses weak dielectric properties and slightly increases resistance to physical impacts. The artifact feeds on the owner’s energy, slightly reducing stamina. Radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string> 	
	
	<string id="st_af_transistor_name">
		<text>Transistor</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_transistor_descr">
		<text>A twisted segment of an electrical grid once used to power trains—somehow transformed into an artifact, first discovered in an anomalous railway tunnel by a team of stalkers working for scientists. Since then, its variants have begun appearing across the Zone. The artifact effectively blocks psi-waves, reducing their impact to near-zero levels—comparable to the Sakharov Dome. It also absorbs a portion of electrical charge, providing moderate protection against discharges. However, its magnetic field is strong enough to attract metal fragments, nails, and small debris—especially in areas cluttered with wreckage. Additionally, it picks up a broad spectrum of electromagnetic frequencies—from radio signals to anomaly noise—and converts them into a constant, low-frequency hum, perceived by many as a soothing ambient tone. Many bearers report reduced anxiety, though the mechanism behind this effect remains unstudied. Its main drawback is considerable weight, which hinders swift movement. Highly radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_metamorf_name">
		<text>Metamorph</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_metamorf_descr">
		<text>Transformed by psi-energy of monstrous strength, an ordinary flowering plant—apparently—has become an artifact. When its pollen is inhaled, the body’s endocannabinoid system activates, providing reliable protection against psi-waves and aiding in physical recovery. It can help close serious wounds and delivers mild healing effects during inhalation. However, the flower's strong scent causes drowsiness, slowing reaction times, causing dizziness, and making the wearer vulnerable in combat. Additionally, bodily tissues become more sensitive to damage—particularly dangerous during firefights or encounters with mutants.   Extremely radioactive and considered quite expensive. Some have even learned to dry it—for brewing or smoking. Dried specimens are of great interest to certain… shady individuals.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_axon_name">
		<text>Axon</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_axon_descr">
		<text>Formed under the influence of extreme psi-waves. Resembles a neuron—thin, translucent filaments with a semi-transparent membrane that faintly pulse when in close proximity to a human. Effectively blocks psi-impact, reduces anxiety, and enhances concentration. Promotes healing of superficial wounds by stimulating localized blood flow. Also acts as a strong dielectric, providing protection against electrical discharges. However, the artifact emits a toxic gas—not merely poisonous, but penetrative: it passes through fabric, metal, plastic, and even dense materials without resistance. Upon contact with skin, it breaks down the epidermal structure, rendering it brittle, hypersensitive to mechanical damage, and drastically reducing resistance to chemical, thermal, and biological threats. Scientists speculate this is not merely an artifact, but a form of life capable of metabolism and excretion of byproducts. Unconfirmed rumors suggest it may influence the bearer’s consciousness—up to the point of “taking control” over their actions. Extremely radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_brain_name">
		<text>Brain</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_brain_descr">
		<text>Resembles the brain of an unknown organism—slightly analogous to a human one. Analysis reveals it is composed of a hybrid of living tissue and an unidentified dense material. The artifact provides exceptional protection against psi-impact, generating its own psi-waves that resonate with external fields and neutralize even the most powerful psychic disturbances. It is said one can walk safely beneath the Radar’s antennas while wearing it. Beyond shielding, the “Brain” accelerates neural conductivity, noticeably enhancing reaction speed and dexterity. This allows for faster combat responses, evading bullets, claws, and sudden attacks with uncanny precision. But this boost comes at a steep cost: it overloads the central nervous system. Fatigue multiplies severalfold—even brief use induces profound exhaustion requiring extended rest. Often accompanied by severe dizziness, loss of coordination, and temporary spatial disorientation—especially during movement or changes in lighting. Dark rumors cling to this artifact: some claim that in critical states—such as severe injury or extreme fatigue—it may attempt to seize control of the bearer. No verified cases exist. Likely just the fevered speculation of greedy traders. Highly radioactive. Extremely valuable.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,125,0,210]Psi Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_night_star_name">
		<text>Nightstar</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_night_star_descr">
		<text>A spherical brown formation surrounded by a dense array of long, pale-yellow spines. A fairly popular and useful artifact. It has undergone significant changes in both properties and appearance.   Slightly increases carrying capacity and provides minor protection against fast-moving objects through its own gravitational field.   If handled carelessly, the spines can deliver painful pricks, causing minor bleeding.   Collectors around the world seek to add one to their collections, driving its price higher than other artifacts of similar tier.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gravi_name">
		<text>Gravi</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gravi_descr">
		<text>An amorphous mass of yellowish-brown color. Formed through prolonged gravitational exposure of metal-containing substances. An ordinary artifact that, over the years, evolved into this form, acquiring new properties. It possesses anti-gravitational qualities, allowing you to carry more equipment in your backpack without feeling the weight. The same field also increases the velocity of objects within its influence, making the bearer move faster—but also amplifying the force of incoming attacks. The artifact’s gravitational component partially suppresses blast waves, reducing their impact. However, due to accelerated molecular motion within its gravitational field, resistance to thermal effects is reduced, and the artifact tends to attract nearby objects that enter its zone of influence. For a long time, the nature of this artifact remained unclear—until Professor Sakharov discovered that "Gravi" emits pulses of gravitational energy at 30-minute intervals. Moderate radioactivity. Solid stats. Great price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_name">
		<text>Goldfish</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gold_fish_descr">
		<text>An artifact resembling a golden-hued stone with growths that vaguely resemble an aquarium fish in shape. A popular, highly sought-after, and fairly expensive anti-gravity artifact. Believed to form when high-voltage electric currents meet extreme temperatures. Widely used among stalkers—it significantly increases carrying capacity by reducing the perceived weight of equipment, thanks to its anti-gravitational properties. Provides excellent protection against blast waves and shrapnel by dispersing impact forces across the body, lowering the risk of injury. Also increases movement speed, likely due to improved muscle coordination and reduced inertia during motion. Despite this, it weakens tissue strength—skin and muscles become more prone to tearing, less flexible, and increasingly brittle. Additionally, although resistant to electricity itself, the artifact slightly reduces the body’s tolerance to heat. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_mahovik_name">
		<text>Flywheel</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_mahovik_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a perforated hollow disc containing two hemispheres within. Generates a very strong anti-gravitational field, significantly reducing backpack weight, and possesses excellent filtration properties—trapping toxins and removing accumulated radioactive particles from the body.   Extremely fragile; can shatter if struck directly, exploding and severely injuring the owner. Feeds on the bearer’s blood, drastically slowing wound healing. Also highly sensitive to high temperatures—it may melt, causing first- to second-degree burns. Despite its drawbacks, it remains in high demand among stalkers engaged in smuggling runs, who can afford to counteract its negative effects. Highly sought-after and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gravitator_name">
		<text>Gravitator</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gravitator_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of a complex structure: eight columns connected at the top and bottom, forming a cage, with a funnel-shaped formation at its center. Generates an extremely powerful anti-gravitational field, allowing the bearer to carry significantly more loot, while also providing solid protection against fast-moving projectiles. Infuses the body with energy, enabling longer periods of running.   However, it rapidly drains the owner’s life force—potentially to fatal levels—acts as an excellent conductor of electricity, and reduces psi-protection. Staring at it for too long causes a strong buzzing sensation in the head, accompanied by a growing, rhythmic hum. Some stalkers claim they’ve witnessed owners of this artifact suddenly vanish in beams of light. Extremely radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_chetki_name">
		<text>Rosary</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_chetki_descr">
		<text>A mica-like formation shaped like a coiled loop with periodic thickenings. Feels and weighs like a metal bracelet, yet is actually composed of countless ultra-thin scales of unknown origin, tightly fused together. The artifact greatly reduces the perceived weight of the backpack, increases muscular strength and endurance, allowing for longer runs and faster movement without fatigue. These effects are especially valued during extended treks across the Zone. Additionally, the mechanical act of fingering the "beads" has a noticeable calming effect. However, the artifact actively drains the owner’s life force, and with prolonged use, dizziness, weakness, and even brief episodes of disorientation may occur. Extremely radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
		
	<string id="st_af_necklace_name">
		<text>Daughter’s Necklace</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_necklace_descr">
		<text>Appears as a simple amber necklace on a thin thread. According to scan data, the entire artifact is composed of a substance unknown to science. It generates a pronounced gravitational field—reducing the perceived weight of carried load by nearly half, allowing the bearer to carry significantly more equipment without fatigue. It also excels at deflecting fast-moving objects. Additionally, the artifact energizes the body, slowing exhaustion during running, while increasing stamina and agility. According to one legend, a stalker’s daughter gave this necklace to her father before his next expedition into the Zone. He never returned, consumed by an anomaly—this necklace was all that remained of him. Or perhaps, it was just a string of beads after all… Extremely radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,0]Anti-Gravity
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>
		
	<string id="st_af_medusa_name">
		<text>Jellyfish</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_medusa_descr">
		<text>An egg-shaped, pale-brown formation with a cave-like lower section. The "Jellyfish" is famous for being one of the first wonders ever brought from the Zone into the outside world. Despite being actively studied by numerous research institutes, little is known about the nature of this common artifact.   It is capable of removing a small amount of radioactive particles—making it valued by stalkers as a form of passive protection against radioactive hotspots. It also generates a fluctuating gravitational field that offers slight protection from fast-moving projectiles.   However, it accumulates a small amount of toxic substances and slightly reduces psi-resistance.   An incredibly common low-tier artifact—still, not entirely useless. Its widespread availability has somewhat reduced its price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_name">
		<text>Wrenched</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_vyvert_descr">
		<text>The "Wrenched" is a grim reminder of the Zone’s effect on living things. Gravitational anomalies twisted, compressed, and bent a bundle of plant roots and branches together, forming a dense, heavy, ugly, stone-like mass.   Over the years, the Wrenched has undergone significant changes in appearance, yet it still retains its modest ability to protect against tearing damage—though this has become secondary. Its main value now lies in its ability to effectively remove radiation from the owner’s body. However, it steadily drains the bearer’s life force and slightly thins the blood, increasing the risk of bleeding. The artifact itself, due to its jagged structure, can easily cut the handler if not handled carefully. Fair price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_baloon_name">
		<text>Bubble</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_baloon_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of several interconnected hollow formations of organic origin. Expensive and incredibly useful. The first specimen was discovered in the Rusty Forest by the legendary mercenary Scar.   Effectively removes radiation and toxic particles from the body. The artifact releases a gaseous substance that energizes the owner, but simultaneously softens tissues, making them more vulnerable to physical damage. Additionally, it emits its own psi-waves, which exert pressure on the bearer’s nervous system—posing a serious risk when combined with external psi-influences. Rather expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string>

	
	<string id="st_af_galaxy_name">
		<text>Galaxy</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_galaxy_descr">
		<text>A spherical artifact of considerable mass. Externally resembles a galaxy trapped within a glass sphere. Possesses strong radiation-filtering capabilities, absorbing radioactive emissions into itself and allowing the bearer to remain in irradiated environments for extended periods. Calms the psyche and strengthens bodily tissues, making them less prone to tearing. However, it severely drains the owner’s energy and life force—evidently feeding on them. It also slightly increases bleeding, drawing blood cells toward itself within a small radius and absorbing them. A stunning, valuable, and expensive artifact, highly sought after by both collectors and scientists.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_propeller_name">
		<text>Propeller</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_propeller_descr">
		<text>An artifact consisting of a hemispherical base from which two rows of blades extend, resembling a turbine or propeller. The structure appears highly ordered, fueling theories about artificial origins. When worn on the belt, its blades begin to spin, absorbing radiation, bullets, excess heat, and toxic particles. However, it also absorbs and attracts lightning strikes, mutant claws, and blood leaking from the bearer’s wounds. There are a few theories about where all this matter disappears to—each more absurd than the last—but none are taken seriously. Slightly increases the weight of items in the backpack due to its gravitational properties. Additionally, because the rotation direction of the blades is unpredictable—capable of suddenly reversing without apparent cause—movement becomes difficult, especially in narrow passages or while running. Recently, rumors have circulated that the artifact can become unstable and suck its owner inside. Most likely, these stories are spread by greedy traders trying to lower its price—there is no confirmed evidence to support them. Extremely expensive and controversial, with unstable, unpredictable properties.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_absorbent_name">
		<text>Absorbent</text></string> 
	<string id="st_af_absorbent_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a spherical lattice structure, with electric discharges flickering inside. Extremely effective at removing radiation—allows the use of highly radioactive artifacts without fear of absorbing a lethal dose, or lets you wander through heavily contaminated areas as if strolling down a boulevard.   Provides solid protection against physical damage by reinforcing both the body and equipment on a molecular level, and offers decent resistance to moderate psi-effects. Holding it in your hands almost instantly dissolves anxiety and mental tension, leaving the mind clear and focused.   But this comes at a price: it intensifies all bleeding. The artifact also acts as an excellent conductor of electricity. It is strongly advised not to carry this artifact near electromagnetic anomalies (including "Electra"-type). Interaction with the anomaly’s electrical discharges may trigger uncontrolled current transfer through the artifact, resulting in severe nervous system damage, burns, or even death. A highly valuable and expensive artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_vint_name">
		<text>Screw</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_vint_descr">
		<text>An artifact very similar to the "Propeller," but with a more complex structure. Some scientists believe it may have artificial origins. Preliminary data suggests it has no negative properties. When worn on the belt, its blades begin to spin, absorbing ionizing radiation, toxic particles, and excess heat. For these qualities, stalkers have given it another nickname—“Conditioner.” However, like the "Propeller," the artifact attracts electrical discharges and actively draws blood from open wounds, potentially worsening fluid loss during injury. Where it sends everything it absorbs remains a mystery yet to be solved. As levels of external anomalous exposure increase—radiation, heat, electricity—the blades spin faster, enhancing absorption. But this also increases physical resistance to movement. Combined with another drawback—its considerable weight—this significantly reduces maneuverability. There are unconfirmed reports suggesting that, when properly activated, it could even be used to decontaminate radiation-polluted areas. Like the "Propeller," rumors circulate about it becoming unstable and sucking in its owner—or even an entire group—but there is no credible evidence to support this. Extremely expensive and very heavy.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,217,102]Anti-Radiation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>	
	
	
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_name">
		<text>Mama's Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_glassbeads_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of two lines of interconnected beads, joined by thin rods extending from a central core. Orange in color, it emits a glow of the same hue. One of the older artifacts, it constantly pulses, emitting waves that have a beneficial effect on the body—boosting metabolism, accelerating wound healing, and warming the bearer.   However, it increases sensitivity to toxins. Also provides slight protection against fast-moving projectiles.   The long-term consequences of using this artifact remain unknown.   Radioactive. Moderate price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_eye_name">
		<text>Eye</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_eye_descr">
		<text>The front part of the artifact resembles a human eye with a fiery hue, while the artifact itself has a teardrop shape and bright red color. Emits a vivid red glow. When not held securely, it tends to jump and float more in the air.   Among seasoned stalkers, there's a belief that the "Eye" brings good luck. Whether true or not, its positive effects are indeed quite powerful.   This artifact accelerates metabolic processes, promoting rapid wound healing, restores life force, and warms the bearer. A weak anti-gravitational field also helps the owner carry slightly more weight.   Radioactive and fragile—it can heat up significantly and cause burns. Secretes a slime that slightly softens bodily tissues.   Can be sold for a high price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_fire_name">
		<text>Flame</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_descr">
		<text>A spherical, semi-transparent formation of fiery color, emitting an orange glow. Popular among experienced mutant hunters, this artifact can seal any wound, healing the owner through intense infrared radiation. The wound-healing effect is so strong that some stalkers claim to have survived even attacks from chimeras. Its fiery nature also provides protection against extreme heat by absorbing a portion of thermal radiation. However, it significantly reduces electrical resistance—acting as an excellent conductor—and weakens physical protection by making tissues more vulnerable to damage. Due to its high effectiveness and striking visual appeal, it can be sold easily for a very good price. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_lavahell_name">
		<text>Hellfire Lava</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_lavahell_descr">
		<text>The artifact consists of an outer shell with openings and an inner sphere that burns with deep red fire. It can be safely held—the warmth it emits is pleasant, not burning the skin.   Capable of healing nearly any wound, restoring a significant amount of the owner’s health, and removing accumulated radiation.   When in use, a strange sensation arises—the feeling that the artifact is watching its bearer. Staring at it is unsettling: the flickering light within appears almost alive, drawing the gaze and causing mild dizziness.   In the presence of fire anomalies, its energy field resonates, dramatically amplifying their thermal effects—a mere approach to a *burner* can result in severe burns.   The artifact is accompanied by a constant low-frequency hum in the head, disrupting focus and impairing combat awareness.   For some reason, it is popular among collectors. Perhaps they enjoy frightening people with it—or hope to heal old wounds?   Very rare and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_glass_beads_name">
		<text>Glass Bracelet</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_beads_descr">
		<text>Structurally similar to the artifact "Mama's Beads," but with its ends fused together, forming a double ring made of light, glass-like material. Accelerates metabolism, triggering regenerative processes—the body fills with energy and warmth. With it, even lethal wounds close before one’s eyes. At the same time, it has an extremely negative effect on the psyche and may drive the bearer insane without sufficient psi-protection. It will inevitably attempt to kill you in zones of chemical and electrical anomalies, as it significantly amplifies their harmful effects. Numerous reports have emerged of people dying mysteriously after coming into contact with this artifact. Extremely radioactive and expensive—its price inflated by greedy collectors.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_mamino_ozherele_name">
		<text>Mother's Necklace</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_mamino_ozherele_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of three strands of beads twisted into a spiral structure resembling a necklace. Externally similar to "Mama's Beads," but with a more complex organization. The beads vary in color, structure, and properties: green ones provide excellent protection against chemical burns, while red beads efficiently absorb excess heat. The most important are the maroon beads—these possess an exceptional tissue coagulation ability. Any wound, no matter how severe, closes within seconds. There have been documented cases of injuries healing around the very object that caused them—be it a claw, bullet, or even a knife. In some cases, severed fingers and cut-off ears have reportedly regrown. However, this activity comes with serious risks. First, the artifact is extremely sensitive to electric fields: when exposed to an electrical discharge, part of the energy is redirected into the bearer, causing internal burns and concussions. Second, despite its powerful coagulation, the artifact reduces overall tissue resistance to mechanical damage—bullets, shrapnel, and blunt impacts deal greater harm than they would otherwise. Scientists believe this is due to redistribution of the body’s resources and structural changes in connective tissue. Highly radioactive, and considered one of the most expensive coagulative artifacts in existence. Rumors circulate about its effects on blood composition and viscosity, but these remain unconfirmed.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_daughter_buses_name">
		<text>Daughter’s Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_daughter_buses_descr">
		<text>Resembles ordinary blue beads. However, scanning data reveals they are made of a substance unknown to science, connected not by a thread, but by a field of unknown nature. Preliminary reports suggest it has no negative properties.   There are numerous theories about its origin—ranging from an artificial construct to a living organism.   Extremely effective at healing wounds: injuries of any severity close within seconds. Reports confirm it has healed gunshot wounds to the head and even reattached severed limbs. Also gently warms the bearer.   According to legend, a stalker’s daughter gave these beads to her father before his latest expedition into the Zone. He never returned—lost in an anomaly. The beads were all that remained. Or… was it actually a necklace?   Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,133,32,12]Coagulation
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_name">
		<text>Battery</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_battery_descr">
		<text>A ribbed, glossy, dark-blue formation with six plate-like layers in the center, where faint electrical discharges can be seen. One of the oldest known artifacts. Acts as a weak insulator, offering slight protection against electric shock. Provides very mild stimulant effects, allowing the owner to run slightly faster and dodge bullets and shrapnel more effectively. A side effect of this stimulation is a slight reduction in the owner’s resistance to psi-waves, along with a minor drop in overall body temperature. Attracts toxic particles to itself. Some stalkers claim that if properly wrapped with specific wires, it can serve as an endless energy source—though there are no confirmed cases. Radioactive. Decent price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_name">
		<text>Shell</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_dummy_dummy_descr">
		<text>The artifact consists of two bluish discs connected by a semi-transparent material of unknown nature. One of the older artifacts.   Protects against electric anomalies by forming a dome around the bearer that dissipates the voltage of electrical discharges—earning it its name. This dome also lowers the internal temperature by a couple of degrees and stops a small portion of fast-moving projectiles.   However, within the dome, it slightly softens objects, making them more vulnerable to physical impact.   The artifact emits weak psionic waves as a byproduct of its metabolic processes, exerting subtle pressure on the psyche.   Radioactive and fairly expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_ice_name">
		<text>Snowflake</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_descr">
		<text>A spherical formation surrounded by numerous long, blue needle-like protrusions. Emits a deep blue glow and faint electrical discharges. Externally resembles the "Kolobok" artifact—though some believe this is the Kolobok, its properties altered after exposure to a powerful electric field. As rare and valuable as its counterpart. Offers solid protection against electric shocks and increases the owner’s muscle tone, thereby enhancing stamina. Additionally improves resistance to burns—likely due to stabilization of heat-sensitive proteins in skin cells, slowing tissue denaturation under high temperatures. However, the artifact reduces overall strength of connective and muscular tissues, increasing the risk of micro-tears during physical exertion. Due to its high radioactivity and its tendency to draw heat from the bearer, stalkers who carry it are sometimes jokingly called "Radioactive Snowflakes". Provides minor protection against fast-moving projectiles. Can overheat in high-temperature environments and cause burns. Lowers psi-protection and may trigger episodes of paranoia, panic, sudden aggression, and spatial disorientation. High price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_svetofor_name">
		<text>Traffic Light</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_svetofor_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of three fused spheres of different colors. Scanning data reveals it consists of three separate, previously unknown artifacts, merged together under conditions of extreme voltage and intense gravitational stress. Why these components are never found individually remains a mystery—possibly their formation only occurs within the most powerful anomalous fields. The artifact efficiently absorbs electrical discharges and generates a weak energy shield around the bearer, capable of deflecting or slowing fast-moving projectiles—including bullets and shrapnel. However, it gradually drains the body’s resources to sustain its field. Even short-term use brings noticeable fatigue; prolonged exposure leads to rapid loss of stamina and slowed reaction time. Extended use heavily overloads the nervous system, potentially with fatal consequences—especially in psi-anomaly zones. Very radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gauss_name">
		<text>Gauss</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gauss_descr">
		<text>Resembles the "Battery" artifact, but has a different structure and properties. It is also known as the "Bright Battery." Presumably formed from an ordinary Battery exposed to extremely high electromagnetic disturbances.   Offers excellent protection against "Electra" anomalies by absorbing electrical energy and storing it internally, later sharing it with the owner to increase stamina. Provides decent resistance to tearing damage and mutant claws that get too close.   However, it rapidly drains the owner’s life force to sustain itself—potentially to fatal levels.   Extremely radioactive, and vulnerable to high temperatures and chemicals. May melt, causing third- to fourth-degree burns.   Rumors persist that some laboratories use it in place of conventional generators.   An extremely valuable artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_reactor_name">
		<text>Reactor</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_reactor_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of five rods connected by caps at the top and bottom. Lightning constantly surges between the rods. Some scientists believe the artifact has artificial origins. Provides excellent protection against electricity by absorbing all nearby discharges, sharing excess energy with the owner—charging them with power, enabling faster and longer movement. Also generates an energy shield around the bearer that effectively stops fast-moving projectiles. However, it is strongly advised not to enter thermal anomalies with this artifact—it heats up significantly on its own and can cause burns; near *burners*, it may even melt its containment case. Among stalkers, there’s a legend that the Zone uses this artifact to remind humanity of where it all began. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_clear_sky_name">
		<text>Clear Sky</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_clear_sky_descr">
		<text>Resembles the "Compass" artifact after exposure to the "Electra" anomaly—retains a similar shape, but now emits a faint pulsing glow. An extremely rare and powerful artifact, known among stalkers as the "Heavenly Compass." Offers high protective efficiency: reliably shields against electric discharges, including powerful emissions and shocks from anomalies like "Electra." Also reduces the risk of chemical burns by stabilizing the skin’s outer layer upon contact with aggressive substances. Furthermore, it is one of the few artifacts capable of removing significant amounts of radionuclides from the body. Yet despite its seemingly flawless profile, prolonged use reveals serious side effects. The artifact greatly increases fatigue—even minimal exertion leaves the bearer feeling deeply exhausted. This is believed to result from the artifact actively drawing essential microelements and organic compounds from the host’s body, likely using them to maintain its own stability, thereby disrupting energy metabolism. There are also unconfirmed rumors of stalkers vanishing without a trace while carrying this artifact. However, given the high demand for it, many such cases could simply be explained by plain looting. Extremely expensive. Most stalkers who find it choose to keep it for themselves—despite the risks.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,74,134,232]Electric Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_name">
		<text>Stone Flower</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_flower_descr">
		<text>This artifact resembles a lump of cheese mixed with gemstones. Its inner parts consist of anomalous crystals with minor gravitational fields that deflect a small portion of fast-moving projectiles. The outer shell slightly boosts endurance and filters out a negligible amount of toxic particles. Scientists still debate whether the crystals inside are aquamarines or apatites, but collectors outside the Zone are willing to pay extra regardless. Reduces heat resistance and may cause burns in high-temperature areas. Emits a fairly strong radiation signature.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_empty_name">
		<text>Empty</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_empty_descr">
		<text>This artifact consists of two disks of organic composition (typically lipids, cellulose, and lignin) with nothing but empty space between them—a result of the unique gravitational field formed at its core, which stabilizes the distance between the disks. Any attempt to push them together or pull them apart will fail due to rapid shifts between positive and negative gravitational forces. Carrying "Empty" makes movement noticeably harder: its gravitational field increases air density around the wearer, slowing the body down. On the upside, it provides decent protection against fast-moving projectiles and slightly reduces backpack weight. The artifact emits vapors as part of its metabolic processes, which, on one hand, accelerate wound healing but are mildly toxic to the wearer. Fairly radioactive. Average market price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string> 
 	
	<string id="st_af_full_empty_name">
		<text>Full Empty</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_full_empty_descr">
		<text>Much like the standard "Empty," this artifact consists of two disks bound by a gravitational field. However, this one isn't truly empty. It's theorized that the extreme gravitational hyperactivity during an emission can overwhelm an "Empty's" natural containment, forcing matter between the disks—where it becomes trapped at the artifact's core. Scientists confirm the matter is organic in origin, suggesting mutants may have been pulled inside and reduced to molecular slurry. Rumors have begun circulating that stalkers themselves sometimes get sucked into their own "Empty" artifacts. Most likely, that's just hearsay. The "Full Empty" exhibits an intensified gravitational field, further enhancing its defensive properties. Unfortunately, it also slows the wearer's movement more noticeably and amplifies the effects of its metabolic vapors. Highly radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string> 
	
	<string id="st_af_planetoid_name">
		<text>Planetoid</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_planetoid_descr">
		<text>A spherical formation with three smaller, multicolored spheres orbiting around it. Scientists have long attempted to replicate something similar in their laboratories—so far, without success. Possesses its own fairly strong gravitational field, which slightly hampers movement and captures most fast-moving objects. Can withstand several high-caliber shots before the gravitational force gradually dissipates. Increases resistance to psi-waves. However, it draws blood from wounds—and attempts to widen them in the process—potentially turning minor injuries into severe hemorrhages. Highly vulnerable to toxins and may poison the bearer when used in areas of chemical anomalies. Extremely radioactive. Fairly expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_glas_diablo_name">
		<text>Devil's Eye</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_glas_diablo_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of two spheres—one outer, porous and uneven, and one inner, dense and monolithic. Generates a powerful gravitational field around the bearer—rumored to be strong enough to stop bursts from heavy machine guns. This field greatly increases resistance to sudden impacts, shrapnel, and bullet wounds: body tissues within its influence enter a state resembling a non-Newtonian fluid—temporarily "liquefying" upon impact, dispersing energy throughout the volume and preventing localized damage. However, this redistribution of mechanical energy reduces resistance to tearing. Stretching or sudden bending may lead to severe injuries, particularly in muscles and connective tissues. Emits aggressive psi-waves that have profoundly negative effects on the psyche. Can trigger delirium and reckless behavior. Some bearers have reportedly gone completely insane. May heat up intensely under high temperatures, causing third- to fourth-degree burns. Extremely radioactive. Expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_devil_flower_name">
		<text>Devil's Flower</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_devil_flower_descr">
		<text>Also known as the “Blossomed Stone Flower”—a more mature form of the “Stone Flower” artifact, forged under monstrous gravitational forces. Denser and stronger than many titanium alloys, its structure exhibits exceptional anomalous resistance to mechanical damage. Its defining trait is a powerful intrinsic gravitational field capable of slowing and even halting fast-moving objects. Protection against firearms approaches that of a tank’s armor: bullets and shrapnel lose their energy, embedding themselves mere millimeters from the bearer’s body before stopping. But such protection comes at a terrible cost. The artifact severely impedes movement—steps become heavy, and sudden motions require effort comparable to carrying an extra 40–50 kg. Its psychic effects are contradictory. On one hand, it emits a mild psi-stabilizing influence; on the other, it overloads the nervous system, lowering the threshold for psychological stress. After several hours of wear, even ordinary anxiety-inducing situations can trigger hysteria, disorientation, or violent outbursts. The artifact actively drains life force, leading to chronic exhaustion. Extremely radioactive. Extremely expensive. Its high efficiency has drawn the attention of military structures across nearly all developed nations—many pay handsomely for samples, despite the risks. Yet it earned its name for a reason: countless rumors persist of sudden madness, disappearances, and bizarre deaths linked to its use.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_magnito_name">
		<text>Magneto</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_magnito_descr">
		<text>An extremely rare mutation of the "Medallion" artifact, occurring only when exposed to monstrously powerful gravitational fields. In the course of transformation, it lost its original properties and acquired new ones. It earned its name due to its exceptionally strong magnetic characteristics: the spatial distortion around it is so pronounced it’s visible to the naked eye—the air above the artifact shimmers like heat haze over a scorching surface, but with a viscous, warping effect. Movement within this field becomes excruciatingly difficult—like wading through thick gelatin: every motion requires twice the effort, rapidly depleting physical reserves, accelerating fatigue, and dramatically increasing recovery demands. Scientists claim that, in theory, it could neutralize even a tank round; in practice, bullets, shrapnel, and even large debris are slowed, deflected, or completely halted 30–50 cm from the bearer’s body. Additionally, thanks to intense infrared emissions, the artifact promotes wound healing and exerts a mild anti-aging effect on tissues. The artifact is extraordinarily radioactive—its radiation levels exceed even Zone standards. Some stalkers warn against playing with it or attempting to reposition its components, as rumors persist it may activate like a black hole and consume everything nearby. Due to its extreme effectiveness and rarity, it is hunted by numerous PMCs and military factions across multiple nations.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,120,120,120]Bullet Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_ring_name">
		<text>Ring</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_ring_descr">
		<text>This artifact consists of two beige-white ring-shaped formations of organic origin. Once set in motion, it will continue spinning indefinitely until manually stopped - a phenomenon that defies the first law of thermodynamics. Scientists believe it inherits gravitational properties from "Vortex"-type anomalies. Provides protection against weak physical attacks, minor psi-wave exposure, and offers slight health regeneration. However, it acts as a natural lightning rod, grounding all electrical currents - wearers should exercise extreme caution around electrical anomalies. Emits mild radiation. Moderately priced.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,220,220,220]1 level</text></string> 
	
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_name">
		<text>Kolobok</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fuzz_kolobok_descr">
		<text>A spherical formation surrounded by numerous dense, long, light-brown needles with a light-brown core. The legendary Kolobok. It provides physical protection, slightly filters radiation, and weakly restores vitality. But this comes at the cost of reduced resistance to anomalous effects. Its needles constantly pierce your body, drawing out radiation but causing persistent bleeding. While it offers minor healing, the wounds it inflicts never fully close. Scientists have circulated reports about the artifact's effects on the wearer's genetic material, though no confirmation exists yet. A worthy price.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,224,224,224]2 level</text></string>
	
		<string id="st_af_urchin_name">
		<text>Hedgehog</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_urchin_descr">
		<text>The "Rusty Hair" anomaly very rarely produces such an artifact. Visually similar to the "Kolobok" artifact, possibly representing a more "mature" version. Provides excellent protection against mutant claws and fangs by increasing skin toughness and reinforcing equipment elements. Raises blood pressure and forces the body to purge significant amounts of red blood cells, effectively removing accumulated radiation. Offers minor healing properties. However, the price for these benefits is substantially reduced resistance to all anomalous effects. In his seminal work "Ionization and Polarization Components of Rare Artifacts," Sakharov noted that this formation's composition possesses critical stability, making laboratory reproduction impossible for decades to come.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,200,100]3 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_name">
		<text>Sea Urchin</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_sea_urchin_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a large white-blue sphere, studded with spines that rhythmically extend and retract in wave-like motions. The spines are rigid but not sharp—difficult to pierce oneself on them, though contact produces a mild tingling sensation. Offers enhanced resistance to tearing by reinforcing both bodily tissues and equipment components, along with solid psi-protection through partial shielding of aggressive psi-waves. It absorbs vast amounts of energy from surrounding lifeforms—and especially from its bearer—resulting in severe depletion of stamina. Capable of accelerating the healing of minor wounds: skin and muscle regenerate faster, particularly after small cuts and bruises. However, this process demands substantial water intake—the body loses fluids at an accelerated rate, causing thirst to spike dramatically. Highly vulnerable to heat: elevated temperatures cause the artifact to glow intensely, risking spontaneous combustion. Extremely radioactive. Fairly expensive. Highly sought after by mutant hunters.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,160,60]4 level</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_pendulum_name">
		<text>Pendulum</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_pendulum_descr">
		<text>An intricate rhomboid lattice formation containing a spherical core. Its possible artificial origin remains unconfirmed, though the artifact's anomalous symmetry and geometric precision cast doubt on natural formation. Provides exceptional protection against blunt trauma and can heal even critical wounds - including internal injuries and multiple fractures. However, using it without proper psi-shielding is virtually impossible. Gradually, the artifact exerts a corrosive psychological effect: inducing aggressive outbursts, escalating paranoia, and complete loss of emotional control. Documented cases exist of stalkers wearing "Pendulum" entering irreversible frenzied states - discarding weapons to attack everything in sight with bare hands. Once triggered, no reasoning was possible; even when restrained, victims would only growl and rant incoherently. Current theories suggest this stems from the dangerously accelerated healing process disrupting normal brain function - potentially through neural hyperactivation or stress mediator overload. Exact mechanisms remain unverified and require further study. Extremely radioactive and exceptionally valuable.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,229,91,130]5 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_volchok_name">
		<text>Spinning Top</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_volchok_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a flattened, lattice-patterned sphere with an intricate starburst structure at its core. Composed of materials unknown to modern science. Some researchers suggest artificial origin due to its perfect symmetry and absence of natural crystallization patterns. Generates an anomalous energy field around the wearer that functions as a protective shield. Most effective against slashing and tearing damage - particularly from mutant claws and fangs. Can also deflect or stop small to medium caliber bullets. Highly prized by mutant-hunting stalkers for its protective qualities. Additionally reduces perceived weight of carried objects - especially useful when transporting trophies and loot. However, the artifact exerts severe psychological effects. Induces hallucinations, anxiety attacks, and visual distortions. Without proper psi-shielding, users experience persistent visions - so vivid and terrifying that some stalkers refuse to speak of them entirely. Others report seeing mutants beyond worst nightmares... Extremely radioactive and requires careful handling. Considered both valuable and rare - particularly undamaged specimens.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,145,61,219]6 level</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_indiliian_name">
		<text>Indilian</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_indiliian_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a sphere, sparsely prickled with needles, shimmering in all the colors of the rainbow. One theory suggests it is either the next evolutionary stage of the “Sea Urchin” or an extremely rare mutation of it. Also known as “The Hunter’s Dream.” Generates a dense energy field that deflects physical attacks—claws, fangs, and even blows from heavy mutants simply glance off without effect. Yet this protective shield constantly drains the bearer’s life energy—even during minimal activity, the owner experiences fatigue, weakness, and profound exhaustion. To compensate, the body demands far more food: appetite surges, and hunger becomes a constant, gnawing presence. It can also absorb high-intensity psi-waves. There’s a tale of a seasoned bloodsucker attacking a stalker bearing this artifact—only to scratch uselessly at the barrier, roaring in frustration. Then came a Controller, attempting mental domination—but the artifact repelled him too. Remarkably, it heals even severe wounds that it failed to prevent in the first place. Strangely enough, no horrific rumors surround this artifact. Which, of course, doesn’t mean you should let your guard down. Extremely radioactive. Extremely expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,180,225,255]Wound Protection
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute</text></string>
	
	
	<string id="st_af_misery_bread_name">
		<text>Anomalous bread</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_misery_bread_descr">
		<text>Old, radioactive bread that someone tossed into an anomaly. But it refused to simply go stale - instead transforming into an artifact. Can be turned into pocket change when needed.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,250,170,100]1 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_glass_name">
		<text>Firefly</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_descr">
		<text>The legendary Firefly. A small glowing orb of honeyed amber, emitting beams of azure light. A single specimen can pull someone standing at death's door back to life. Some studies suggest it may even reverse cellular aging. But it comes with a host of drawbacks: drastically reduces resistance to all forms of damage - bullets, mutant claws, or anomalies alike. Owners must mitigate these weaknesses through careful use of combat artifacts or anomaly protection gear. Yet its regenerative properties are so potent that one could theoretically ignore the disadvantages altogether and simply outheal the damage. Highly radioactive and exorbitantly priced.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_death_lamp_name">
		<text>Death Lamp</text></string>  
	<string id="st_af_death_lamp_descr">
		<text>"Big, red, and cursed" - that's how most stalkers describe this artifact, though some call it the "Devil's Seed." A sinister blood-red rose that grants its bearer superhuman strength. Its eerie glow repels and protects against mutants. Yet the artifact rapidly drains the user's vitality, sapping both energy and body heat - potentially fatal without precautions. And it's radioactive as hell. Worse still, it erodes the wearer's willpower, often causing dizziness, hallucinations, and/or visions. Many refuse to speak of what they've seen in these visions; those who do describe waking nightmares. No wonder traders are reluctant to buy it, offering far lower prices than other top-tier artifacts. The Death Lamp was first discovered years ago by a trio of veteran stalkers. Shortly after delivering it to scientists at Yantar, two of the three were found dead - their faces frozen in pure terror. The third stalker's fate remains unknown. After the incident, research team members reported severe sleep disorders in the following days... Handle this artifact with extreme caution.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string> 
	
	<string id="st_af_steik_name">
		<text>Steak</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_steik_descr">
		<text>An artifact in the form of a massive chunk of meat wrapped in a transparent casing. Judging by its size, it’s likely all that remains of a large mutant that accidentally entered a gravitational anomaly. It effectively quells hunger, slightly accelerates regeneration, and restores thirst—but drastically reduces psionic resistance and may drive one insane. It commands a high price and is quite radioactive. Attempts have been made to use it to solve the world’s hunger crisis, but the negative effects have never been eliminated.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_ladder_name">
		<text>Ladder</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ladder_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a lattice structure that rotates around its axis. Provides decent protection against chemical and thermal burns, while also restoring health through infrared wave emission - which doubles as a good heat source. However, it significantly reduces combat protection and drains the wearer's energy to sustain itself. A fairly useful artifact overall. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_ice_s_name">
		<text>Ice</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ice_s_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed within the “Electra” anomaly. Consists of a complex geometric structure of interwoven tubes and conductive pathways, resembling an electrical circuit diagram. Provides decent protection against electricity and infuses the wearer’s body with energy—but at the cost of significantly reduced defense against mutants. A transparent liquid, visually identical to pure water, constantly seeps from the artifact. Studies confirm it is heavy water (D&#8322;O): usable as an emergency drinking reserve when no other sources are available, but only in minimal quantities and under dire circumstances—prolonged consumption causes metabolic disruption. The artifact is extremely vulnerable to high temperatures and may melt, causing severe burns. While worn, it siphons body heat to sustain itself. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_guiding_star_name">
		<text>Guiding Star</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_guiding_star_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped like a sphere with large protruding needles. This artifact excels on long expeditions. It suppresses hunger, boosts energy levels, and lightens backpack weight through its antigravitational properties - allowing for fewer rest stops. The trade-off is significantly reduced psi-protection, making encounters with Controllers particularly dangerous. The sharp needles easily cause injuries, especially during combat. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,240,130,70]2 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	
	<string id="st_af_ferroconcrete_name">
		<text>Ferroconcrete</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ferroconcrete_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of four concrete fragments with interwoven rebar - likely remnants of some former structure. Possesses a unique gravitational field that significantly reduces backpack weight while synthesizing essential amino acids, proteins, fats and carbohydrates, decreasing the need for frequent meals. The perfect artifact for long expeditions. However, it amplifies impact damage by softening tissues and severely weakens chemical protection. Extremely radioactive and expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_dark_angel_name">
		<text>Dark Angel</text></string>
    <string id="st_af_dark_angel_descr">
		<text>An artifact with a sapphire core. Resembles the "Bat" artifact - possibly a more mature version. Dramatically boosts your energy reserves while absorbing excess electricity for self-sustenance. However, it also drains your blood, vitality, and body heat as secondary energy sources. The life-force consumption is so extreme that careless owners have reportedly dropped dead before even realizing what's happening. Extreme caution is mandatory when handling this artifact. Extremely radioactive and prohibitively expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_chips_name">
		<text>Chips</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_chips_descr">
		<text>An artifact composed of four petal-like structures fused together in a shell-like formation. Typically forms in thermal and chemical anomalies. Displays a brown coloration with gray speckles. Its resemblance to meat chips earned it the name. Scans revealed traces of organic matter within the artifact. Provides decent thermal protection and enables survival in toxic environments, but at the cost of constantly leaching iron from your blood - causing severe hemorrhaging. It also consumes a significant portion of the wearer's vital energy. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_gorgon_name">
		<text>Jellyfish Gorgon</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_gorgon_descr">
		<text>A large, irregularly shaped iridescent mass with numerous tendrils, flickering faint multicolored lights. It significantly enhances combat and physical protection, regenerates serious wounds, improves overall health, and provides warmth. But the price for these benefits is extreme vulnerability to anomalous effects - excessive heat, electricity, and chemically aggressive environments. The artifact can gradually drive you insane through its aggressive psi-waves. Rumors persist it might even have zombifying properties. Collectors would undoubtedly kill to acquire such a treasure. Consequently, it commands a hefty price. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_krest_name">
		<text>Stone Cross</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_krest_descr">
		<text>An anomalous formation with an intricate structure of green arches resembling a cross. Primarily emerges in acid anomalies. Absorbs radiation and toxins like a sponge. It can simultaneously sustain multiple artifacts on your belt while filtering radiation from both your inventory and nearby anomalous zones. The trade-off? It drastically reduces resistance to all physical impacts. Also nicknamed "The Clover," many believe it brings good luck. A quite valuable and expensive artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_wish_name">
		<text>Dream</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_wish_descr">
		<text>An electrostatic artifact named by its first discoverer, Sanya the Philosopher. An exceptionally valuable find. Excels at purging radiation and energizing the body, but significantly weakens protection against chemical anomalies. Definitely not recommended for expeditions through "Soda" fields. Operates by draining body heat for sustenance. Commands a premium price for its class - coveted equally by collectors for its rarity and stalkers for its utility. Scientists remain particularly fascinated by its properties.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,90,40]3 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_glass_star_name">
		<text>Glass Star</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_glass_star_descr">
		<text>A crystalline, hoop-shaped substance the color of sea foam. When knowledge of its existence spread, it became highly sought-after among collectors. Stalkers prize it equally - it's one of the most valuable mental shielding artifacts, allowing safer use of psyche-draining artifacts without risking insanity. Also provides excellent protection against electricity. Fragile to a fault - a well-placed shot can make it detonate like a grenade, shredding its wearer with shards. Continuously drains body heat during use. Extremely radioactive. Many stalkers believe finding one foretells immense luck or salvation from impending doom. Can be sold for fortunes - another form of mental relief during hard times.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,100,100,255]Cools
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_sprut_name">
		<text>Octopus</text></string>
    <string id="st_af_sprut_descr">
		<text>An artifact resembling an octopus with tentacles protruding from its sides. One of the most potent anti-radiation artifacts in the Zone. When activated, its tentacles extend and penetrate beneath the skin, aggressively filtering radionuclides from the body. However, the tentacles simultaneously inject anticoagulant compounds, dramatically increasing bleeding risk. The artifact feeds on the host's vital energy during operation - precise radiation exposure calculations are crucial, as miscalculations can prove fatal. Some stalkers compensate with supplementary artifacts. Several victims have been discovered as desiccated mummies, still entwined in the artifact's tentacles. This demands expert handling to mitigate dangerous side effects. Some perimeter zone hospitals employ it as a last-resort treatment. Extremely expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_compass_name">
		<text>Compass</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_compass_descr">
		<text>A spherical black formation covered in cracks, from which white prisms protrude. A legendary artifact. Capable of suppressing anomalous activity in nearly any anomaly. Possesses its own gravitational field, allowing the bearer to carry significantly more weight. Yet this power demands a blood price: the sharp prisms slice through any protection, causing severe hemorrhaging. It also drains a substantial portion of the wearer's life force - potentially fatally. Extremely radioactive and prohibitively expensive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
		
	<string id="st_af_doom_name">
		<text>Rock</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_doom_descr">
		<text>An artifact resembling bizarre interwoven horn-like structures with a central sphere, appearing as if formed from cooled lava. Numerous disturbing rumors surround it - from unexplained disappearances to victims spontaneously combusting in full view. One account tells of a drunken bandit who, armed only with this artifact and his trusty knife, flew into a rage against a pack of Bloodsuckers - not only surviving but butchering them all. Though they ultimately had to put him down when he completely lost his mind and attacked everything in sight. The artifact dramatically enhances protection against mutant attacks, hardening skin to steel-like durability while accelerating regenerative processes. It floods the user with energy, making blood literally boil in their veins. But prolonged use takes a catastrophic toll on the psyche, inevitably transforming the wearer into a deranged beast consumed by bloodlust. Extremely radioactive and exorbitantly priced.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_bloodcompass_name">
		<text>Dark Compass</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_bloodcompass_descr">
		<text>This artifact resembles the standard "Compass," but with a distinctive crimson hue. Exceptionally effective at healing its bearer, it enhances muscle tone - allowing for extended running and increased carrying capacity - while generating a protective field that excels against all physical threats. It also provides outstanding radiation cleansing. Upon contact, it floods your entire body with warmth. However, it severely weakens protection against anomalies and emits intensely aggressive psi-waves capable of inducing madness. An extraordinarily valuable - and costly - artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_monolith_name">
		<text>Volat Emerald</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_monolith_descr">
		<text>The artifact's origins remain shrouded in mystery, with only a handful of specimens ever found in regions close to the Zone's center. This unique artifact actively responds to its environment, resonating and adapting to surrounding conditions. It provides exceptional protection against various Zone anomalies and holds the rare distinction of being one of the few artifacts that can be safely carried on a belt without a protective container. However, merely holding it induces immediate disturbing sensations - as if your flesh is necrotizing and bones turning brittle. These effects are so pronounced they'll make you desperately seek additional protective gear or supporting artifacts.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_fire_cristall_name">
		<text>Fire Crystal</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_cristall_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed in anomalous zones under extreme temperatures. Externally resembles the “Crystal” artifact, but appears as if entirely composed of frozen flame—its facets shimmering in radiant reds and oranges, emitting a warm, pulsing glow. It does not burn upon contact; instead, it generates a stable thermal shielding field that effectively insulates the wearer from fire and high heat. Simultaneously, it provides warmth—valuable in cold, damp regions of the Zone. It also has the ability to expel radioactive particles and replenish the body’s energy reserves, partially alleviating fatigue. Yet the artifact exerts a profound influence on the central nervous system. It suppresses natural sleep mechanisms: neutralizing adenosine, blocking melatonin production—effectively depriving the bearer of the ability to fall asleep. Prolonged wear or intense visual fixation on its facets may trigger severe psionic disturbances—up to persistent, hyper-realistic hallucinations. A very few stalkers have dared to describe what they saw: the sensation of falling into an endless flame, screams, the stench of burning flesh, visions indistinguishable from reality—in one word, they described seeing the very biblical Hell...
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_amyoba_name">
		<text>Amoeba</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_amyoba_descr">
		<text>An artifact shaped as a complex geometric figure with multiple facets, composed entirely of living matter. Believed to represent a new, heat-resistant lifeform. Maintains a constant 16°C thermal field around itself while protecting the wearer from extreme temperatures. Also provides excellent electrical insulation, neutralizing electric shocks. However, it drastically reduces the body's resistance to toxic environments—so severely that approaching within 10 meters of chemical anomalies without proper protection becomes suicidal. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_plenka_name">
		<text>Pellicle</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_plenka_descr">
		<text>A flexible, elastic patch of unknown organic material, resembling a resilient bio-film. The substance exhibits extraordinary tensile strength and can stretch under mechanical stress without tearing—composed of an organic compound not yet identified by science. Its primary property is exceptional resistance to chemical burns. Additionally, the Pellicle offers partial protection against kinetic damage: when struck by a bullet or shrapnel, it behaves like a ceramic armor plate—locally deforming, absorbing impact energy, and fragmenting the projectile. But in doing so, its own structure sustains damage. Microfractures remain on the surface after each hit, progressively degrading its protective capabilities. Recovery requires time—several hours to a full day, depending on the extent of trauma. For this reason, it cannot be relied upon as dependable defense under sustained fire. It draws energy directly from the wearer’s body, drastically reducing stamina—so severely, in fact, that it may induce paralysis if the host is already weakened. Since its discovery, scientists have labored tirelessly to replicate the material under controlled conditions—but so far, without success. Highly prized by artifact hunters. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_oko_name">
		<text>All-Seeing Eye</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_oko_descr">
		<text>An artifact resembling a human eye in appearance - hence its name. Provides excellent protection against chemical burns and decent psi-shielding by feeding on toxic substances and aggressive psi-waves. However, it also feeds on your blood - and will do everything to obtain it: not only preventing wound healing but actively trying to expand injuries. Even minor wounds become potentially fatal when wearing this artifact. Rumors persist it's literally the Zone's own eye, allowing it to observe everything happening for kilometers around. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_akkumulyator_name">
		<text>Accumulator</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_akkumulyator_descr">
		<text>According to theoretical researchers, this artifact appears to be a hybrid of the "Battery" and "Empty" artifacts—a combination only possible under simultaneous extreme conditions: intense pressure, powerful radiation fields, and chemically aggressive environments. Such transmutation-inducing natural conditions have only been recorded in a few deep Zone locations, though no verified sightings of this artifact near them exist. The artifact offers one of the highest known levels of protection against chemical burns. Its energy field stabilizes molecular structures in skin and subcutaneous tissues, blocking toxic compound penetration and neutralizing corrosion at the cellular level. Effective against both acids and alkalis, including complex anomalous reagents found in acid anomalies. Additionally, it energizes the wearer's body. Not only does it conduct electricity exceptionally well, but it inexplicably amplifies electric shocks. Carrying it near "Electra" anomalies is extremely hazardous. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,230,45,20]4 level (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_vaselisk_kld_name">
		<text>Basilisk</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_vaselisk_kld_descr">
		<text>An electrostatic artifact—a semi-transparent sphere of condensed field, faintly pulsing in the dark. One of the rarest and most valuable artifacts in the Zone. Provides comprehensive protection against anomalous effects: effectively neutralizing psionic fields, gravitational distortions, thermal surges, and electromagnetic pulses. It also generates a localized anti-gravity field, reducing the perceived weight of items in your backpack and significantly easing movement under heavy load. Simultaneously, it aids in the expulsion of radionuclides from the body, slowing radioactive accumulation. Yet despite its advantages, the Basilisk has a grave flaw: it disrupts tissue integrity at the cellular level, rendering skin, muscles, and connective tissues brittle and fragile. Few have heard of it—and those who have hunt its fragments relentlessly. Persistent rumors claim it is often found near bodies torn to shreds—as if it draws something terribly dangerous nearby... But that’s probably just superstition.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_geliy_kld_name">
		<text>Helium</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_geliy_kld_descr">
		<text>An electrostatic artifact that emits a gaseous substance with profoundly beneficial effects on the wearer’s body: it rapidly heals wounds, restores vitality, and infuses the organism with energy. It also efficiently purges radiation and alleviates dizziness. Due to these properties, it is in immense demand. Though no overt side effects are observed, a moderate increase in physiological demands has been noted—the body begins consuming more energy and resources, manifesting as heightened needs for food, water, and sleep. No rumors circulate about it. Apparently, this is because few who possess it wish to speak of it openly.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)</text></string>		
	
	<string id="st_af_midi_name">
		<text>Snail</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_midi_descr">
		<text>A chemical artifact composed of two hemispheres connected by one central and three lateral tubes, filled with a slowly circulating transparent fluid. Some theorize it is a newly discovered life form. It exhibits strong detoxifying properties: efficiently expels radionuclides from the body, slowing radiation accumulation and accelerating recovery after exposure. It also forms a protective barrier at the skin and mucous membrane level, increasing resistance to chemical burns and toxic fumes. One of its key effects is the reduction of food and water requirements. While worn, the body enters a low-metabolic state—cellular respiration stabilizes, energy utilization becomes more efficient, and glycogen and fluid reserves are consumed at a significantly slower rate. There are fragmented, contradictory accounts claiming the artifact can attach itself to the flesh—and once bonded, cannot be removed. Most likely, these are just rumors. An extremely valuable artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_klaksa_name">
		<text>Blot</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_klaksa_descr">
		<text>An artifact formed within gravitational anomaly zones. Resembles a flower: four latticed “petals” converge at the center, forming a cavernous core with a porous internal structure. Externally similar to the “Amoeba” artifact—fueling theories of a possible hybrid origin, perhaps the result of two anomalous entities merging under intense gravitational compression. It excels at expelling radiation and generates a localized gravitational field that partially shields the backpack and gear, reducing perceived weight and easing strain on the musculoskeletal system. While worn, the artifact exerts a gentle calming effect on the central nervous system—slightly increasing drowsiness, especially during periods of low activity. Simultaneously, motor coordination improves, granting a marginal boost in maneuverability. A few unverified rumors claim the artifact can “close,” reversing its gravitational polarity and pinning the wearer beneath its own crushing weight—a fate nearly always fatal in the Zone. Yet this effect has never been observed during testing. An extremely valuable artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_padshi_angel_name">
		<text>Fallen Angel</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_padshi_angel_descr">
		<text>A complex structure of pure silicon: a central sphere from which three protrusions extend, each terminating in a thickened node, and two flat, wing-like plates on the opposite side. Its origin remains unknown. Scientists continue to debate whether it is a living organism—given that it consists entirely of silicon. The artifact drastically reduces the need for food and water by optimizing metabolic consumption at the cellular level. Yet this efficiency comes at a steep cost: rapid accumulation of fatigue. The nervous system recovers poorly, muscular exhaustion sets in faster, and concentration deteriorates. It allows survival for several days without resupply—free from hunger or dehydration. It also provides a deeply comforting warmth during cold periods. A few tales circulate among stalkers claiming the artifact can grant wishes—if one learns how to communicate with it. Extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_itching_low_name">
		<text>Sponge</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_itching_low_descr">
		<text>The artifact takes the form of a lattice sphere with small, symmetrically arranged gray spheres nestled in its recesses. Preliminary data indicates no negative properties. It excels at radiation cleansing and provides excellent protection against thermal and chemical burns by significantly reinforcing tissue resilience. The artifact emits gentle warmth when held. Rumors suggest it may explode if subjected to simultaneous thermal and chemical exposure. If true, there's unfortunately no one left to confirm it.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,0,0]Unique
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,58,220,69]Absolute (unique)
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Temperature: %c[255,238,153,26]Warms
		\n</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_blackraven_name">
		<text>Object "Black Raven"</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_blackraven_descr">
		<text>The scientists' first attempt at creating an artificial artifact. Many ecologists had complained about the inability to carry sufficient supplies and equipment into the field. Numerous anti-gravitational artifacts were collected, broken into fragments, and reassembled—resulting in severe instability in the final product. The artifact was intended to solve logistical problems, but instead increased staff mortality rates by approximately 200%. While its gravitational field does facilitate carrying more supplies, it simultaneously amplifies the velocity of all incoming objects and attacks by 50 times—invariably causing instant death to the user regardless of the projectile's size or attack's weakness. Scientists successfully removed all radiation from the component artifacts during experimentation. Extremely expensive and dangerous. These prototypes were eventually abandoned, and now only daredevil stalkers use them to haul larger quantities of loot.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,255,255]Basic (synthetic)</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_serpantin_name">
		<text>Object "Serpentine"</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_serpantin_descr">
		<text>When scientists asked how fast a human could run with the help of an artifact, they set out to create one specifically for this purpose. After several failed experiments—resulting in side effects such as accelerated aging of the owner or extremely rapid fat cell combustion, leading to anorexia if the subject wasn’t sufficiently overweight—the final product was named "Serpentine." The original goal of enhancing the owner’s speed was achieved. The artifact’s energy regeneration properties significantly aid in prolonged running. After multiple refinements, the radiation emission was completely reduced to zero, and the remaining drawbacks were limited to reduced psi-protection from overuse and the inability of blood to clot while the artifact is active. It is known that the scientific leadership overseeing the project became immensely wealthy from the patent. Recommended for use in combination with other artifacts.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,255,255]Basic (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_jaba_name">
		<text>Object "Toad"</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_jaba_descr">
		<text>The artifact consists of a network of brittle green lines intricately intertwined. When exposed to air, its surface quickly develops a dark crust resembling dried film. This artifact resulted from experiments with the "Bubble" artifact, conducted as part of psi-radiation shielding development. Scientists specifically aimed to neutralize the effects of the "Brain Scorcher" at Yantar. While demonstrating high effectiveness in suppressing psi-effects, its complex manufacturing process and prohibitive cost prevented mass production - even for ecologists' needs. Notable drawbacks include extreme sensitivity to anomalous phenomena, particularly electrical effects. These artifacts occasionally appear for sale when scientists decide to liquidate portions of their stockpiles.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,255,255]Basic (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_sparklercore_name">
		<text>Core of "Sparkler"</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_sparklercore_descr">
		<text>The "Sparkler" artifact underwent immersion in fluoroantimonic acid, completely dissolving its hazardous outer shell and enabling full utilization of its more durable core's potential. All negative properties were eliminated while beneficial effects became more pronounced. Not entirely synthetic, yet impossible to find in the wild and inaccessible without invasive modifications. The senior researcher overseeing this development secured lifelong financial comfort through patent royalties from this technology.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,255,255]Basic (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_stonebloodcore_name">
		<text>Core of "Stone Blood"</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_stonebloodcore_descr">
		<text>Sakharov's own discovery. Created by leaving a "Stone Blood" artifact overnight in the scientists' artifact furnace set at a constant 500°C. The radioactive outer shell was completely incinerated along with all negative properties. The original "Stone Blood" provided reliable chemical burn protection but couldn't withstand high temperatures. After transformation, its internal structure underwent fundamental reorganization: the artifact's fireproof core not only survived but became enhanced. The new artifact lost its chemical resistance but gained exceptional fire and heat protection. Curiously, it became significantly heavier than its original form for unknown reasons. Stalkers' attempts to replicate this process using natural anomalies like "Burner" have failed - the brief, unstable flame bursts can't provide the sustained, even heat required for complete protective layer dissolution.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,255,255,255]Basic (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_cry_electra_name">
		<text>Tears of Electra</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cry_electra_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification obtained through stable fusion of the Eye and Sparkler artifacts. One of the first successfully documented and reproducible modified artifacts. During transmutation, the Sparkler gets completely absorbed while the Eye's structure undergoes reorganization - its surface becomes transparent sky-blue and emits faint luminescence in darkness. The artifact effectively purges accumulated radiation and helps restore the body's energy balance, eliminating fatigue symptoms and boosting stamina. However, the structural transformation comes with a side effect: the modified crystal disrupts molecular stability in the skin's protective barriers, resulting in reduced resistance to chemical burns.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_grandma_beads_name">
		<text>Granny's Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_grandma_beads_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification resulting from the fusion of Mama's Beads and Wrenched artifacts. During transmutation, the Wrenched gets completely absorbed while Mama's Beads develop a deep blue hue. The resulting modification generates a temporal field that significantly slows down incoming bullets and shrapnel, providing protection against critical injuries. However, it's radioactive and reduces resistance to electric shocks.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_dikobraz_name">
		<text>Porcupine</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_dikobraz_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification created through fusion of the Hedgehog and Crystal artifacts. During transmutation, the Crystal gets completely absorbed while the Hedgehog becomes encased in an exceptionally hard cellular structure. Its sole beneficial property is blocking substantial amounts of radioactive emissions. The reduced stamina seems a modest price to pay for wandering irradiated lands without fear of lethal radiation exposure.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_pelt_name">
		<text>Hide</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_pelt_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification created through fusion of the Sponge and Stone Blood artifacts. During transmutation, the Stone Blood gets completely absorbed while the Sponge becomes encased in a yellow cellular structure resembling a piece of large snake skin. Reduces susceptibility to all chemically aggressive environments and provides burn protection. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_fier_dummy_name">
		<text>Fiery Shell</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fier_dummy_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification resulting from fusion of the Shell and Pin artifacts. During transmutation, the Pin gets completely absorbed while the Shell develops an orange-red hue. Beyond mitigating impact damage, it enhances the wearer's stamina. However, this comes with increased vulnerability to electricity. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_bright_soul_name">
		<text>Bright Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_bright_soul_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification created through fusion of the Soul and Battery artifacts. During transmutation, the Battery gets completely absorbed while the Soul takes on a blue hue. Accelerates wound healing and restores lost health. However, it feeds on the wearer's energy and softens tissues, making them more susceptible to physical damage.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_steel_kolobok_name">
		<text>Steel Kolobok</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_steel_kolobok_descr">
		<text>A synthetic modification resulting from fusion of the Kolobok and Gravi artifacts. During transmutation, the Gravi gets completely absorbed while the Kolobok becomes encased in a steel-like metallic substance. Enhances tissue resistance to tearing and improves ballistic protection. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,153,205,255]Modifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_cry_fier_name">
		<text>Tears of Fire</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cry_fier_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification created through fusion of the Tears of Electra modification and Flame artifact. During transmutation, the Flame gets completely absorbed while the Tears of Electra transform into a teardrop-shaped magma cluster maintaining a constant temperature of 36.7°C. Provides decent radiation cleansing and thermal protection. A rather valuable artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>	

	<string id="st_af_great_grandma_beads_name">
		<text>Great-Granny's Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_great_grandma_beads_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification resulting from fusion of the Granny's Beads modification and Bubble artifact. During transmutation, the Bubble gets completely absorbed while Granny's Beads transform into black with burgundy speckles. Offers superior bullet and shrapnel protection compared to its predecessor through enhanced temporal field reinforcement. Additionally, it now accelerates wound healing. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>


	<string id="st_af_electric_dikobraz_name">
		<text>Electric Porcupine</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_electric_dikobraz_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification created through fusion of the Porcupine modification and Moonlight artifact. During transmutation, the Moonlight gets completely absorbed while the Porcupine shifts to a white-blue coloration resembling the Snowflake artifact. Boasts unparalleled radiation cleansing capabilities, significantly reduces fatigue, and provides decent psi-protection. However, it becomes extremely vulnerable to electric shocks.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_scales_name">
		<text>Scales</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_scales_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification resulting from fusion of the Hide modification and Goldfish artifact. During transmutation, the Goldfish gets completely absorbed while the Hide transforms into various shades of blue, resembling a piece of scale armor from some large reptile or fish. Provides excellent protection against chemically aggressive environments and burns while restoring vitality. Its unique effect on tissues reduces susceptibility to tearing, but simultaneously makes blood vessels extremely brittle - even minor bleeding may prove fatal. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_bright_shell_name">
		<text>Radiant Shell</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_bright_shell_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification created through fusion of the Fiery Shell modification and Snowflake artifact. During transmutation, the Snowflake gets completely absorbed while both disks of the Fiery Shell become coated with a glass-like material, with a bluish slime-like substance forming between them. Further enhances impact resistance and energizes the body. Now also provides decent psi-protection. However, its vulnerability to electric shock has proportionally increased. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_fire_soul_name">
		<text>Fiery Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_fire_soul_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification resulting from fusion of the Bright Soul and Fireball artifacts. During transmutation, the Fireball gets completely absorbed while the Bright Soul takes on a crimson hue, resembling the Flame artifact. Enhances wound healing and health regeneration even further. Unlike its predecessor, it now replenishes the wearer's energy instead of draining it. However, it still softens tissues, making them increasingly vulnerable to physical damage - so you'll want to find a secure location before using its healing properties.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_titan_kolobok_name">
		<text>Titanium Kolobok</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_titan_kolobok_descr">
		<text>A synthetic mesomodification created through fusion of the Steel Kolobok and Empty artifacts. During transmutation, the Empty gets completely absorbed while the Steel Kolobok becomes encased in a bluish-gray metallic substance with titanium-like structural properties. Further enhances tissue resistance to tearing and improves ballistic protection. Now also provides decent burn protection. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,114,163,255]Mesomodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_cry_witches_name">
		<text>Witch's Tears</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cry_witches_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hypermodification created through fusion of the Tears of Fire mesomodification with Goldfish and Meat Chunk artifacts. During transmutation, the component artifacts get completely absorbed while the Tears of Fire transform into a teardrop-shaped cluster of viscous green matter. Provides decent radiation cleansing and protects against both thermal and chemical burns.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_grandma_burer_beads_name">
		<text>Burer's Granny Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_grandma_burer_beads_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hypermodification created through fusion of the Great-Granny's Beads mesomodification, Full Empty artifact, and a Burer mutant's hand. During transmutation, both the Full Empty and Burer tissue get absorbed, while the Great-Granny's Beads become covered in a flesh-red epithelial-like layer with distinctly unsettling appearance. Incorporating the Burer's genetic material significantly amplified the temporal field's strength and radius. A wearer can now survive even direct sniper rifle hits. Additionally, the artifact restores vitality and heals even critical injuries. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_sopli_dikobraz_name">
		<text>Snot Hedgehog</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_sopli_dikobraz_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hyper-modificate produced through a complex transmutation of the mesomodificate Electric Porcupine with the Bubble and Meat Chunk artifacts. During fusion, the original components are entirely consumed, and the structure of the Electric Porcupine undergoes radical alterations: the artifact acquires an acid-green hue and becomes permanently coated in a viscous, semi-transparent slime that seeps through microscopic cracks. Exhibits exceptional bioactivity: capable of eliminating over half of accumulated radiation from the body within a minute, effectively halting both internal and external bleeding, and reliably replenishing energy reserves, eradicating signs of exhaustion. However, practical application is complicated by the artifact’s physical properties. The secreted slime is not only highly unpleasant to touch and leaves persistent residue on equipment, but also possesses extremely high electrical conductivity. It forms a stable conductive layer on the artifact’s surface and around its bearer, drastically increasing the risk of electric shock. Because of this, the artifact is extremely hazardous in electromagnetically active zones. Nevertheless, its unique regenerative and detoxifying capabilities render it highly valuable under controlled conditions—provided adequate external insulation and appropriate protective gear are employed.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_shield_name">
		<text>Shield</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_shield_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hypermodification created through fusion of the Scales mesomodification with Flame and Meat Chunk artifacts. During transmutation, the component artifacts get completely absorbed while the Scales transform into a dirty-yellow substance resembling chitinous armor from some large insect. Provides excellent protection against both chemical and thermal burns while enhancing tissue resistance to tearing and accelerating wound healing. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_moon_shell_name">
		<text>Lunar Shell</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_moon_shell_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hypermodification created through fusion of the Radiant Shell mesomodification with Moonlight and Black Spray artifacts. During transmutation, the component artifacts get completely absorbed while the Radiant Shell's disks transform into a lunar surface-like texture and coloration. Dramatically enhances impact resistance, replenishes bodily energy reserves, and provides decent psi-protection. However, its vulnerability to electric shock has intensified proportionally. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_cristall_soul_name">
		<text>Crystalline Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_soul_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hypermodification created through fusion of the Fiery Soul mesomodification with Seed of the Oasis and Flame artifacts. During transmutation, the component artifacts get completely absorbed while the Fiery Soul develops green hues and a verdant glow. Dramatically accelerates wound healing and health restoration while continuously replenishing energy reserves. While it still softens tissues - making them more vulnerable to physical damage - this effect has been significantly reduced compared to previous versions.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>		
	
	<string id="st_af_diamond_kolobok_name">
		<text>Diamond Kolobok</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_diamond_kolobok_descr">
		<text>A synthetic hyper-modificate formed through the fusion of the mesomodificate Titanium Kolobok with the artifacts Snowflake and Full Empty. During transmutation, the component artifacts are fully absorbed, and the Titanium Kolobok becomes encrusted with a crystalline structure resembling diamond. Grants the bearer significantly increased resistance to lacerations, reduces the effects of high temperatures and chemically aggressive environments, and generates a field capable of deflecting a portion of fast-moving projectiles. The primary drawback is its radioactivity.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,142,127,255]Hypermodifier (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_cry_chimera_name">
		<text>Chimera's Tears</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cry_chimera_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute created through fusion of the Witch's Tears hypermodification, Meat Chunk artifact, and the heart/skin of a Chimera mutant. During transmutation, the Meat Chunk and mutant components get completely absorbed while the Witch's Tears shift to an acid-yellow coloration. Provides exceptional protection against both chemical and thermal burns while purging significant amounts of accumulated radiation. Incorporating the Chimera's genetic material has granted this absolute superior wound-healing and health-restoration capabilities.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_great_grandma_burer_beads_name">
		<text>Burer's Great-Granny Beads</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_great_grandma_burer_beads_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute created through fusion of the Burer's Granny Beads hypermodification, Flame artifact, and a Burer mutant's hand and brain. During transmutation, both the Flame and mutant components get completely absorbed while the Beads transform into an acid-red, bone-like appearance resembling violently extracted skeletal matter. Incorporating additional Burer genetic material has exponentially amplified the temporal field's strength and radius. A wearer can now survive direct hits from high-caliber sniper rifles. The artifact provides exceptional healing - capable of recovering even the most critical injuries - while continuously restoring health. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_stone_dikobraz_name">
		<text>Stone Hedgehog</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_stone_dikobraz_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the hyper-modificate Snot Hedgehog, the artifact Goldfish, and the claw and horn of a "Chimera" mutant. During transmutation, the Goldfish artifact and the monster's parts are completely absorbed, and the Snot Hedgehog becomes encased in an extremely hard substance resembling granite. Efficiently eliminates any level of radiation—no matter how extreme—within seconds. The bioactive compounds derived from the chimera’s claws and fangs grant strong resistance to electric shock, effectively reduce bleeding, and steadily recharge the body’s energy reserves.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_scalp_control_name">
		<text>Controller's Scalp</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_scalp_control_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the hyper-modificate Shield, the artifact Flame, and the hand and brain of a "Controller" mutant. During transmutation, the Flame artifact and the biological components are fully absorbed, and the Shield becomes coated in a violet substance with white veining and a complex internal structure. The incorporation of genetic material from a Controller mutant has endowed this absolute with exceptional resistance to psi-radiation, strong protection against thermal and chemical burns, and a sustained energy-supplying effect that significantly reduces the bearer’s sensation of hunger. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>
	
		<string id="st_af_pudding_name">
		<text>Pudding</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_pudding_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the hyper-modificate Lunar Shell, the artifact Full Empty, and the hand and leg of a "Snork" mutant. Genetically, snorks are not vastly different from humans, yet only Snork tissue can be used to create this artifact. During transmutation, the Full Empty artifact and the biological components are completely absorbed, and the Lunar Shell becomes encased in a brown substance whose structure vaguely resembles... chocolate. The resulting object bears a striking likeness to a chocolate pudding—hence its name. Effectively neutralizes impact forces and provides strong protection against electric shock. Additionally, it efficiently replenishes the body’s energy reserves and increases the bearer’s carrying capacity. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_cristall_soul_bengal_name">
		<text>Bengal's Crystalline Soul</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_cristall_soul_bengal_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. According to legend, named after the first stalker who independently discovered the method of creating this artifact. Formed through the fusion of the hyper-modificate Crystalline Soul, the artifact Moonlight, and the tentacles and hide of a "Bloodsucker" mutant. During transmutation, the Moonlight artifact and the biological components are fully absorbed, and the Crystalline Soul shifts to a range of deep violet hues. This absolute excels at restoring health and healing even the most severe wounds—capable of pulling you back from the very edge of death. In addition, it efficiently energizes the body and increases carrying capacity, traits highly valued among stalkers. Radioactive, so its radiation must be counterbalanced with another artifact that removes radiation. An extremely expensive and strikingly beautiful artifact.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_giants_younger_brother_name">
		<text>Little Brother of the Giant</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_giants_younger_brother_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the hyper-modificate Diamond Kolobok, the artifact Fireball, and the hand and hide of a "Pseudobear" mutant. During transmutation, the Fireball artifact and the biological components are completely absorbed, and the Diamond Kolobok shifts to a reddish-brown hue. The incorporation of genetic material from a Pseudobear mutant has endowed this absolute with excellent resistance to impact and tearing, decent protection against chemical and thermal burns, and a sustained energy-supplying effect that reduces the need for food. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_simbiont_name">
		<text>Symbiont</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_simbiont_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. One of the oldest known recipes for creating an absolute. Formed through the fusion of the artifacts Jellyfish, Stone Blood, Nightstar, and Itcher. During transmutation, Stone Blood, Nightstar, and Itcher are fully absorbed, and the Jellyfish becomes encrusted with a stony formation and shifts its glow to a deep violet. Provides excellent protection against psi-effects, rapidly heals even the most severe wounds, steadily energizes the body, and offers solid resistance to impact and tearing. Radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>
	
	<string id="st_af_ruby_flower_name">
		<text>Ruby Flower</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ruby_flower_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the artifacts Stone Flower, Crystal, Lobster Eyes, and Ring. During transmutation, Crystal, Lobster Eyes, and Ring are fully absorbed, and the Stone Flower shifts to a vivid red hue, its internal crystals transforming into large rubies. It has a distinctly ominous appearance, yet commands immense value due to the presence of these sizable rubies within its structure, as well as its exceptional properties. Provides outstanding protection against all forms of direct physical trauma by interacting with bodily tissues, reinforcing them at the molecular level. Its only drawback—radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_ruby_gravi_name">
		<text>Ruby Gravi</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ruby_gravi_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the artifacts Gravi, Crystal, Flash, and Pin. During transmutation, Crystal, Flash, and Pin are fully absorbed, and the Gravi becomes coated in a crystalline substance resembling ruby in structure. Effectively restores health and stops bleeding. Additionally, due to its significant anti-gravitational field, it reduces backpack weight and steadily energizes the bearer, greatly diminishing the sensation of hunger. Its only drawback—radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>

	<string id="st_af_ruby_battery_name">
		<text>Ruby Battery</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_ruby_battery_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. Formed through the fusion of the artifacts Battery, Crystal, Empty, and Lobster Eyes. During transmutation, Crystal, Empty, and Lobster Eyes are fully absorbed, and the Battery becomes coated in a crystalline substance resembling ruby in structure. Provides excellent protection against electric shock and steadily energizes the body. Also offers decent defense against fast-moving projectiles. Its only drawback—extremely radioactive.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>	
	
	<string id="st_af_navigator_name">
		<text>Navigator</text></string>
	<string id="st_af_navigator_descr">
		<text>A synthetic absolute. The first—and to date, only—successful attempt to synthesize a new artifact not from "low-level" components, but from artifacts that have appeared in the Zone very recently. This recipe came at great cost: failed experiments, at best, ended in powerful explosions and severe laboratory damage; at worst, the consequences had to be classified. Nevertheless, through trial and error, it was discovered that when the artifacts Compass, Dark Compass, Fire Crystal, and Glass Star are combined in a precise manner, they fuse into a homogeneous crystalline mass, which subsequently forms an artifact vaguely resembling a mollusk shell. Its structure bears no resemblance to any known analog and is, in essence, a new chemical element. Provides exceptional protection against all forms of anomalous influence—similar to the Compass, but significantly stronger—and so far displays no negative side effects. At least, none have been found yet.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,255,255,255]Synthetic
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,120,230,130]Absolute (synthetic)</text></string>		
	
	<string id="st_af_black_name">
        <text>Black Stone</text></string>
    <string id="st_af_black_descr">
        <text>Truly, an amazing thing. The Black Stone protects against broadly considered adversity but instead is slowly killing the owner. Some stalkers suspect the artefact is a shard of the Monolith.
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Type: %c[0,80,80,80]Unknown
		\n%c[0,0,150,0] • %c[255,140,140,140] Level: %c[255,80,80,80]Unknown</text></string>
	
	
</string_table>